Stella & Yuha appear at 03:32
Stella & Yuha muncul 03:32
[Bae Seongjae] This is the Minnesota Wild uniform. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ini seragam Minnesota Wild. Iya.
[Staff] Okay
[Staff] Iya
[Bae Seongjae]  I'll record the opening comments.
[Bae Seongjae] Akan mulai rekam opening.
[Bae Seongjae] Perfect
[Bae Seongjae] Sempurna
[Bae Seongjae] Hello everyone, welcome to Bae Seongjae's TEN on Sunday, March 1st, 2026
[Bae Seongjae] Halo semuanya. Minggu, 1 Maret 2026 di Bae Seongjae's TEN
[Bae Seongjae] Welcome. I'm Bae Seongjae. Our first song was Hearts2Hearts' STYLE
[Bae Seongjae] Selamat datang. Saya Bae Seongjae. Lagu pertama Hearts2Hearts STYLE
[Bae Seongjae] Today's headline was Hearts2Hearts finding their perfect
[Bae Seongjae] telah kami putar. Headline hari ini adalah warna sempurna Hearts2Hearts di ulang tahun pertama
[Bae Seongjae] color on their 1st anniversary. Uh, in 2025 alone, there were about
[Bae Seongjae] mereka. Eh, tahun 2025 lalu ada sekitar 70-80 tim yang debut sebagai idol K-pop
[Bae Seongjae] 70-80 teams that debuted as K-pop idols. Among them, surviving and having their own team color
[Bae Seongjae] Di antara mereka, bertahan hidup dan memiliki warna tim sendiri serta
[Bae Seongjae] and making their songs known to the public isn't easy. After debuting and sweeping nine rookie awards
[Bae Seongjae] memperkenalkan lagu ke publik bukanlah hal mudah. Debut dan selama 1 tahun menyapu
[Bae Seongjae] in one year, girl group Hearts2Hearts with their members' balanced charm and addictive house dance tracks that
[Bae Seongjae] sembilan penghargaan rookie, girl group Hearts2Hearts dengan pesona seimbang para member dan sekali dengar
[Bae Seongjae] keep spinning in your head once you hear them, consistently pushed forward with razor-sharp
[Bae Seongjae] terus berputar di kepala, lagu house dance yang sangat adiktif terus mereka dorong sambil menunjukkan
[Bae Seongjae] performances to gradually make their name known, and now a year after debut,
[Bae Seongjae] performa presisi sehingga perlahan dikenal dan sekarang sudah lewat 1 tahun debut
[Bae Seongjae] they're finding their color and their new songs are getting great reactions. And
[Bae Seongjae] sambil menemukan warna mereka, lagu baru juga responnya sangat bagus. Dan
[Bae Seongjae] Hearts2Hearts' original content is also getting good reactions. These bubbly members have great
[Bae Seongjae] Hearts2Hearts konten sendiri juga responnya bagus. Keceriaan member-member ini, chemistry-nya juga
[Bae Seongjae] chemistry and their honest daily life moments are getting really good reactions. Today these ladies are coming
[Bae Seongjae] bagus dan kehidupan sehari-hari yang jujur responnya sangat bagus. Hari ini mereka datang ke Bae TEN
[Bae Seongjae] to Bae TEN. Everyone, welcome them with uncle smiles and let's have a fun time
[Bae Seongjae] Kalian sambut dengan senyum paman sambil menghabiskan waktu yang menyenangkan
[Bae Seongjae] together. Now, today is the day for the girl group guest corner you're always waiting for and looking forward to,
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Nah, hari ini adalah hari segmen undangan girl group yang selalu kalian tunggu, Produce 1077
[Bae Seongjae] Produce 1077, and SM's youngest girl group Hearts2Hearts'
[Bae Seongjae] Dan girl group bungsu SM, Hearts2Hearts
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha and Stella are here as representatives. Please wait a moment for our meeting with the '07-liners Nutella duo,
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha dan Stella hadir sebagai perwakilan. Pertemuan dengan duo '07-liners Nutella
[Bae Seongjae] and for Bae Seongjae's TEN, if you come to our YouTube
[Bae Seongjae] tunggu sebentar ya. Bae Seongjae TEN sesuai waktu rekaman di YouTube
[Bae Seongjae] channel or Chzzk during recording time, you can watch the full
[Bae Seongjae] channel hijau Chzzk kalian bisa lihat video penuh seluruh proses rekaman sebelum diedit
[Bae Seongjae] unedited recording process. Especially for Produce 1077, there are many edited parts,
[Bae Seongjae] Terutama Produce 1077 banyak bagian yang diedit
[Bae Seongjae] so make sure to check out
[Bae Seongjae] jadi pasti tonton versi penuh
[Bae Seongjae] the full version. We'll be back after the commercial.
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Dengar iklan dulu, nanti balik lagi.
[Bae Seongjae] Is it on?
[Bae Seongjae] Nyala ga?
[Staff] Yes.
[Staff] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, I want to eat a Nutella sandwich.
[Bae Seongjae] Wah, pengen makan sandwich oles Nutella.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, okay, here
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, nah, ini
[Bae Seongjae] it's marked.
[Bae Seongjae] sudah di-marking.
[Bae Seongjae] 97 97, same age, right?
[Bae Seongjae] 97 97 nomor gabungan ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Welcome, welcome, welcome. Oh my, thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] Selamat datang. Selamat datang. Selamat datang. Aduh terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Welcome.
[Bae Seongjae] Selamat datang.
[Bae Seongjae] Thank you for coming and rushing over like this.
[Bae Seongjae] Kerja keras dan langsung datang begini terima kasih.
[Stella] Oh, there it is.
[Stella] Oh ada di sini.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes, yes, yes. It's on here so all the sound goes in too.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Iya. Iya. Ini nyala jadi suaranya masuk semua.
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Everyone's saying they can't believe it.
[Bae Seongjae] Wah katanya pada ga percaya.
[Stella] It's an honor. We're honored. Please take care of us.
[Stella] Ini kehormatan. Kami yang merasa terhormat. Mohon bantuannya.
[Bae Seongjae] Please take care of us. Please take care of us.
[Bae Seongjae] Mohon bantuannya. Mohon bantuannya.
[Bae Seongjae] Those born in '07 are now
[Bae Seongjae] Kelahiran '07 sekarang
[Stella] This year.
[Stella] Tahun ini.
[Stella] We became adults. Congratulations.
[Stella] Baru jadi dewasa. Selamat ya.
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Terima kasih.
[Stella] Wow. Wow. Amazing.
[Stella] Wah. Wah. Gila.
[Bae Seongjae] There are a lot of uncle fans here too.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh uncle fans-nya banyak banget.
[Stella] Ah, hello uncles.
[Stella] Ah, uncle fans halo.
[Bae Seongjae] Uncles, older uncles, and grandfathers are here too.
[Bae Seongjae] Uncle fans, pakde, ada kakek juga di sini
[Stella] Ah, grandfather
[Staff] Ah, kakek
[Bae Seongjae] Yes, grandfather,
[Bae Seongjae] Kakek ya,
[Staff] indeed.
[Staff] ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Is your manager treating you well?
[Bae Seongjae] Manager baik sama kalian?
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Stella] Yes. He treats us so well.
[Stella] Ya. Baik banget sama kita.
[Stella] Have you eaten?
[Stella] Sudah makan?
[Bae Seongjae] Dinner, ah, you haven't eaten, right? Oh my, it's late
[Bae Seongjae] Makan malam ah, belum ya? Aduh telat
[Bae Seongjae] What did you eat?
[Bae Seongjae] Makan apa tadi?
[Stella] Uh, chicken and pizza
[Stella] Eh ayam pizza
[Bae Seongjae] Chicken... for someone who's actively promoting, you ate really well. Yeah
[Bae Seongjae] Ayam, untuk yang lagi aktivitas lumayan banyak makannya ya.
[Stella] I love eating
[Stella] Aku suka makan soalnya
[Yuha] Mm
[Yuha] Mm
[Staff] Chicken
[Staff] Ayam
[Yuha] Ah, since we're together, are you from SM?
[Yuha] Ah karena bareng, SM ya?
[Bae Seongjae] Me?
[Bae Seongjae] Saya?
[Bae Seongjae] It's SM C&C, so yes, we could say we're from the same group. Oh amazing.
[Bae Seongjae] SM C&C jadi ya bisa dibilang satu grup. Ah gila.
[Bae Seongjae] As a fellow SM... senior... when did you join SM?
[Bae Seongjae] Lumayan SM sun- sunbae, kapan masuk SM?
[Yuha] 2017.
[Yuha] Tahun 2017.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, you're a great senior then.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah sunbae besar banget.
[Bae Seongjae] I'm 2024. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Saya 2024. Ya.
[Stella] Ah
[Stella] Ah
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, you're 7 years my senior.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh 7 tahun lebih junior.
[Stella] I'm 2023
[Stella] Aku tahun 23
[Bae Seongjae] You're almost 2 years my senior.
[Bae Seongjae] Hampir 2 tahun lebih senior.
[Bae Seongjae] 2017?
[Bae Seongjae] Tahun 17?
[Yuha] Yes. When I was young.
[Yuha] Ya. Waktu kecil.
[Bae Seongjae] So when you were 10?
[Bae Seongjae] Berarti umur 10?
[Yuha] 11 years old.
[Yuha] 11 tahun.
[Bae Seongjae] At 11 years old. Oh my.
[Bae Seongjae] 11 tahun. Aduh.
[Bae Seongjae] Please take care of us, senior.
[Bae Seongjae] Mohon bantuannya sunbae
[Bae Seongjae] How many hours of sleep do you get these days?
[Bae Seongjae] Sekarang tidur berapa jam?
[Yuha] Now that promotions started, I can't sleep.
[Yuha] Sekarang mulai aktivitas jadi nggak bisa tidur
[Stella] We can't sleep much now.
[Stella] Sekarang banyak nggak bisa tidur.
[Bae Seongjae] Can't sleep, right? Sleep in the car.
[Bae Seongjae] Nggak bisa tidur ya. Tidur di mobil.
[Stella] Yes. That's right. During waiting time.
[Stella] Ya. Bener. Waktu nunggu.
[Stella] Mm.
[Stella] Mm.
[Staff] Ah, let's test this once.
[Staff] Ah, sekali test ya.
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Please give us a greeting.
[Bae Seongjae] Salam sekali aja.
[Staff] Yes.
[Staff] Ya.
[Staff] Uh,
[Staff] Eh,
[Staff] Shall we start with Stella? [Stella] Hello. I'm Stella from Hearts2Hearts.
[Staff] Mulai dari Stella dulu ya? [Stella] Halo. Saya Stella dari Hearts2Hearts.
[Stella] I'm so happy to be here today.
[Stella] Senang banget bisa datang hari ini.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh my, your voice is so nice.
[Bae Seongjae] Aduh suaranya bagus banget.
[Yuha] Thank you.
[Yuha] Terima kasih.
[Yuha] Hello. I'm Yuha from Hearts2Hearts. Please take care of us.
[Yuha] Halo. Ini Yuha. Mohon bantuannya.
[Staff] Oh, thank you.
[Staff] Ah terima kasih.
[Staff] When you speak, since the MC is here, we do it like this but
[Staff] Waktu kalian bicara, karena MC ada di sini jadi begini
[Staff] the microphone needs to be close to your mouth for good audio. So always
[Staff] Mikrofon harus dekat dengan mulut biar suaranya masuk dengan baik. Jadi selalu
[Staff] when you speak into the microphone, keep it close.
[Staff] Waktu bicara ke mikrofon, dekati ya.
[Stella] Yes.
[Speaker] Ya.
[Speaker] Got it.
[Speaker] Baik.
[Bae Seongjae] Bae Seongjae will keep going until we meet 1,077 amazing female stars.
[Bae Seongjae] Bae Seongjae akan terus bersama sampai bertemu 1077 bintang wanita yang sedang naik daun.
[Bae Seongjae] Produce 1077.
[Bae Seongjae] Produce 1077.
[Bae Seongjae]  Today's guests, Rookie Award 9-time winners since debut
[Bae Seongjae] Tamu hari ini, pemenang 9 penghargaan rookie
[Bae Seongjae] Their 1st anniversary, new song RUDE comeback, double celebration making every day happy. Bold and
[Bae Seongjae] Comeback lagu baru RUDE di ulang tahun debut pertama, kebahagiaan berlipat ganda setiap hari. Berani dan
[Bae Seongjae] cute and lively Gen Z girl group Hearts2Hearts' Nutella duo, Yuha and Stella,
[Bae Seongjae] imut dan ceria, girl group Gen-Z Hearts2Hearts, duo Nutella Yuha dan Stella
[Bae Seongjae] welcome!
[Bae Seongjae] Selamat datang berdua.
[Stella] Hello.
[Stella] Halo.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, nice to meet you. Yes
[Bae Seongjae] Ah senang bertemu kalian. Ya
[Bae Seongjae] How about introducing yourselves one by one? [Stella] Yes. Yes. Hello. I'm Stella from Hearts2Hearts.
[Bae Seongjae] Bagaimana kalau satu per satu perkenalan diri? [Stella] Ya. Ya. Halo. Ini Stella dari Hearts2Hearts.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh my, thank you. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Aduh, terima kasih. Ya.
[Yuha] Hello. I'm Yuha from Hearts2Hearts.
[Yuha] Halo. Ini Yuha dari Hearts2Hearts.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes, nice to meet you.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya, senang bertemu.
[Bae Seongjae] So, we do this broadcast with the chat window open. Bae TEN. Yes,
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, kami siaran dengan chat room terbuka seperti ini. BaeTen. Ya,
[Bae Seongjae] so since it's live, you don't need to be nervous. These people are all nice. Yes. They just can't
[Bae Seongjae] Karena ini live jadi tidak perlu gugup. Mereka semua baik-baik kok. Ya. Sekarang tidak bisa
[Bae Seongjae] talk back. That's right.
[Bae Seongjae] bicara. Begitu.
[Bae Seongjae] These people are very RUDE. Yes. They're RUDE uncles but yes, still
[Bae Seongjae] Mereka sangat RUDE. Ya. Para paman yang RUDE tapi ya tetap
[Bae Seongjae] they'll be very warm to you. Yes yes
[Bae Seongjae] akan sangat hangat pada kalian. Ya ya
[Bae Seongjae] So Yuha and Stella together, we saw the Nutella combo. Uh, how do
[Bae Seongjae] Nah Yuha Stella digabung jadi kombinasi Nutella. Eh kalian
[Bae Seongjae] you find the chat? What's your first impression?
[Bae Seongjae] bagaimana kesan pertama melihat chat itu?
[Yuha] Uh, really
[Yuha] Eh beneran
[Bae Seongjae] RUDE, right? Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] RUDE kan? Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] They're very RUDE people. Yes. And shy. Yes. They're RUDE to me
[Bae Seongjae] Sangat RUDE. Ya. Mereka malu-malu. Ya. Sama aku
[Bae Seongjae] so don't be too
[Bae Seongjae] RUDE jadi jangan terlalu
[Bae Seongjae] flustered, please
[Bae Seongjae] bingung ya tolong
[Bae Seongjae] They're only RUDE to me.
[Bae Seongjae] Mereka RUDE cuma sama aku aja.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, you started music shows this week and you're doing another music show today and
[Bae Seongjae] Eh mulai minggu ini kalian mulai musik show dan hari ini baru selesai musik show juga kan
[Bae Seongjae] coming here, so you look so bright. Yes. You were also an MC, right?
[Bae Seongjae] jadi terlihat sangat segar dan ya. MC juga baru selesai kan?
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Oh my, congratulations.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Aduh selamat ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Are the other members resting now? Or do they have other schedules? [Stella] They went home.
[Bae Seongjae] Anggota lain sekarang istirahat? Atau ada jadwal lain? [Stella] Mereka sudah pulang.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, but only you two worked hard to come here. Thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah tapi cuma berdua yang datang dengan semangat begini. Terima kasih.
[Stella] Not at all.
[Stella] Tidak apa-apa.
[Bae Seongjae] So let's go to the promotional time. Uh, we'll play Hearts2Hearts' new song RUDE as background music.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah sekarang waktu promosi besar-besaran. Eh lagu baru Hearts2Hearts RUDE akan diputar sebagai backsound.
[Bae Seongjae] While the song plays, please do the team introduction and song promotion that every team does.
[Bae Seongjae] Selama lagu diputar, tolong lakukan perkenalan tim dan promosi lagu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Let's start right away.
[Bae Seongjae] Langsung mulai.
[Staff] Going in.
[Staff] Mulai sekarang.
[Bae Seongjae] So Hearts2Hearts, since this is our first meeting, could you introduce your team name? Yes. We
[Bae Seongjae] Nah Hearts2Hearts ini pertama kali ketemu jadi tolong perkenalkan nama tim? Ya. Kami
[Stella] Hearts2Hearts means heart to heart, and we want to convey our hearts through our music and performances
[Stella] Hearts2Hearts artinya dari hati ke hati, kami ingin menyampaikan hati kami melalui musik dan performance
[Stella] through our music and performances.
[Stella] melalui musik dan performa kami.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, what a beautiful name. Hearts. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah namanya cantik banget. Heart ya.
[Bae Seongjae] And this is SM's first 8-member girl group in 4 years and 3 months since aespa.
[Bae Seongjae] Dan ini grup beranggotakan 8 orang pertama dari SM Entertainment setelah aespa, setelah 4 tahun 3 bulan.
[Staff] Yes.
[Staff] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] S2U, are there any advantages to having many members?
[Bae Seongjae] S2U, apa keuntungan punya banyak member?
[Yuha] Uh, when ordering delivery food, the menu variety is diverse.
[Yuha] Eh, waktu pesan makanan delivery menunya bisa beragam.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, so you can order different things and everyone can eat.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah bisa pesan semuanya buat dimakan ya.
[Yuha] We can eat eight different things.
[Yuha] Bisa makan delapan jenis makanan.
[Bae Seongjae] One bite each. Uh, are there any members who are sensitive about having their food taken?
[Bae Seongjae] Satu gigitan masing-masing. Eh, ada yang sensitif soal makanannya direbut gak?
[Yuha] We don't have that, I think we're okay.
[Yuha] Kami gak ada yang begitu, kayaknya oke-oke aja.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh really? Uh, so you order enough. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh gitu ya? Eh, berarti pesan cukup banyak ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Are there any disadvantages to having many members?
[Bae Seongjae] Kekurangan punya banyak member ada gak?
[Stella] The waiting time is long. That's right.
[Stella] Waktu tunggunya lama. Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Waiting time.
[Bae Seongjae] Waktu tunggu.
[Stella] Yes. And prep time is long too.
[Stella] Ya. Waktu persiapannya juga lama.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, like going to the salon or using the bathroom and such.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah kayak ke salon atau pakai kamar mandi gitu-gitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] How are you using your dorm right now?
[Bae Seongjae] Sekarang asramanya gimana?
[Yuha] Yes.
[Yuha] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Eight people in one dorm?
[Bae Seongjae] Delapan orang di satu asrama?
[Yuha] We split up by a few people [Bae Seongjae] Ah, I see. Uh, on the 20th you released your new single album
[Yuha] Dibagi beberapa orang [Bae Seongjae] Ah, begitu. Eh, tanggal 20 kemarin kalian rilis album single baru
[Bae Seongjae] RUDE!. Looking at the song title, there's an exclamation mark.
[Bae Seongjae] RUDE!. Kalau lihat judul lagunya ada tanda serunya.
[Bae Seongjae] How should I say this? RUDE?
[Bae Seongjae] Ini harus dibaca gimana, RUDE! gitu?
[Stella] Uh, kind of like RU-, like RU-
[Stella] Eh, agak seperti RU- gini, RU-
[Staff] Ah, I did it too harshly, that was tacky. I
[Staff] Ah, saya terlalu kencang jadi norak ya.
[Bae Seongjae] That's tacky. Not RUDE like that, but RU-
[Bae Seongjae] Ini yang norak. Bukan RUDE! tapi RU-
[Bae Seongjae] Yes, everyone should say RU-. Yes. Could you introduce what kind of song it is?
[Bae Seongjae] Ya, kalian harus bilang RU- ya. Lagu ini tentang apa?
[Yuha] Uh, RUDE! is a house genre dance song.
[Yuha] Eh RUDE! itu lagu dance bergenre house.
[Yuha] Uh, it's a song with very cute rebellion about not being bound by the rules set by the world.
[Yuha] Eh, lagu yang berisi pemberontakan lucu bahwa kami gak mau terikat sama aturan dunia.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, the song is so good. Today, based on our recording, you did your first music show and
[Bae Seongjae] Ah lagunya bagus banget. Hari ini berdasarkan rekaman ini kalian baru selesai music show pertama
[Stella] came running here - how was the stage reaction? S2U cheered for us so
[Stella] dan langsung ke sini, gimana reaksi di panggung? S2U memberikan dukungan yang sangat hangat
[Stella] passionately
[Stella] jadi
[Stella] Yes. Our hearts felt so warm.
[Stella] ya. Hati kami jadi sangat hangat.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, this is really a great start.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah ini awal yang bagus banget.
[Bae Seongjae] And Yuha, you're the intro fairy with such a pretty voice, for this song RU-
[Bae Seongjae] Dan Yuha punya warna suara cantik banget, kamu peri pembuka lagu, untuk lagu kali ini RU-
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, did I cut it too short?
[Bae Seongjae] Ah terlalu pendek ya?
[Stella] RUDE! Ah, that was good.
[Stella] RUDE! ah bagus kok.
[Bae Seongjae] DE!. Could you possibly do a little a cappella live of RUDE!'s intro?
[Bae Seongjae] RUDE!. Bisa live acapella pembuka RUDE! sedikit?
[Yuha] Yes.
[Yuha] Ya.
[Yuha] Should I do it?
[Yuha] Boleh?
[Bae Seongjae] Start. [Yuha] Who said
[Bae Seongjae] Mulai. [Yuha] Siapa bilang
[Yuha] ordinary things are boring. Everything as I want.
[Yuha] yang biasa itu membosankan, semuanya sesuka hati.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow.
[Bae Seongjae] Wah.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, thank you. Yes. Some people said this is what radio is about. Ears
[Bae Seongjae] Aduh terima kasih. Ya. Ada yang bilang ini baru radio. Telinga
[Bae Seongjae] melting. Voice fairy. As expected of SM. Yes. Someone said their eardrums feel refreshed
[Bae Seongjae] Meleleh. Peri suara. Memang SM. Ya. Ada yang bilang gendang telinganya jadi segar.
[Bae Seongjae] too.
[Bae Seongjae] dan
[Bae Seongjae] And February 24th was your first debut anniversary. Congratulations.
[Bae Seongjae] Dan tanggal 24 Februari kemarin adalah ulang tahun debut ke-1 kalian. Selamat ya.
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, you had your first fan meeting last weekend for your first anniversary.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, karena ulang tahun debut ke-1, kalian mengadakan fanmeeting pertama akhir pekan lalu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. How was the fan meeting? [Yuha] It was our very first fan meeting
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Gimana fanmeetingnya? [Yuha] Ini fanmeeting pertama kami
[Yuha] and some members cried, and it was our first time in a space with just our S2U fans
[Yuha] ada member yang nangis juga dan bareng S2U fans kami di ruangan yang isinya
[Yuha] so it felt really new.
[Yuha] cuma fans aja itu juga pertama kali jadi rasanya baru banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah, someone said time really flies, yes,
[Bae Seongjae] Ya, ada yang bilang waktu cepat banget ya,
[Bae Seongjae] right.
[Bae Seongjae] bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Suyeon Gongu asked what's the most memorable episode from the past year
[Bae Seongjae] Suyeon Gongu-nim bertanya, selama 1 tahun aktivitas kemarin, episode paling berkesan
[Bae Seongjae] of your activities?
[Bae Seongjae] apa?
[Stella] Personally, I think I'll never forget our debut showcase
[Stella] Aku pribadi showcase debut kami benar-benar gak bisa dilupain kayaknya
[Stella] since it was our first time performing on stage and meeting fans for the first time, so I was really
[Stella] soalnya pertama kali naik panggung juga dan pertama kali ketemu fans jadi waktu itu deg-degan banget
[Stella] nervous but it was really impressive.
[Stella] tapi itu yang paling berkesan kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. So it was your first time showing yourselves, how did you feel at that moment?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. Jadi karena pertama kali tampil kan, waktu itu gimana rasanya pas
[Bae Seongjae] Or did you feel like you wanted to show more but had some regrets?
[Bae Seongjae] momen itu? Atau ada rasa pengen nunjukin lebih banyak lagi gitu?
[Stella] Since it was our first time, it was a bit disappointing, but I feel proud because I think we did our best.
[Stella] Karena pertama kali jadi agak nyesel sih tapi rasanya udah maksimal jadi bangga.
[Bae Seongjae] Nice. I see. Now, for your first anniversary, you donated 50 million won under your fan club name
[Bae Seongjae] Keren. Begitu ya. Nah, untuk peringatan 1 tahun, untuk dukungan remaja putri kalian donasi
[Bae Seongjae] S2U to support women and youth. Wow, whose
[Bae Seongjae] 50 juta won atas nama fanclub S2U. Wah, ini beneran ide siapa
[Bae Seongjae] idea was this?
[Bae Seongjae] ini?
[Yuha] All of our members discussed it together, since it's our first anniversary, let's do something meaningful
[Yuha] Semua member bareng-bareng, karena ulang tahun ke-1 jadi pengen buat hal yang bermakna
[Yuha] so we did it.
[Yuha] gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, such a large amount. Yes, already as rookies
[Bae Seongjae] Wah, jumlah besar. Ya, rookie udah
[Bae Seongjae] And following the Korean fan meeting, throughout March you have New York North America showcase, Jakarta
[Bae Seongjae] Dan setelah fanmeeting Korea, sepanjang bulan Maret ada showcase New York Amerika Utara, fanmeeting Jakarta
[Bae Seongjae] fan meeting, right?
[Bae Seongjae] kan?
[Yuha] Yes.
[Yuha] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. You're also preparing overseas performances. What are you preparing?
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Konser luar negeri juga lagi dipersiapkan. Apa aja yang kalian persiapkan?
[Yuha] Oh, we're preparing to show RUDE and also many cover songs, and we plan
[Yuha] Eh, RUDE kali ini sama banyak lagu cover juga mau kami tunjukin, lagi dipersiapkan dan ya. Yang
[Yuha] to show all the setlists we did in Korea. Yes.
[Yuha] di Korea kemarin setlist-nya semua bakal kami tunjukin. Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, I see. Yes. You must be really busy right now, can't even sleep properly, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, begitu ya. Ya. Sekarang lagi gak bisa tidur sibuk banget kan?
[Bae Seongjae] But when you go overseas, you might get some sleep on the flight, right? Yes, that's right.
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau ke luar negeri bisa istirahat dikit di perjalanan kan? Ya, bener.
[Bae Seongjae] In the year since debut, you've won rookie awards
[Bae Seongjae] Debut sampai 1 tahun, kalian menang rookie award
[Bae Seongjae] nine times. Wow, really
[Bae Seongjae] sampai 9 kali. Wah, beneran
[Bae Seongjae] you became the artist with the most rookie award wins last year. Do you have any acceptance speech
[Bae Seongjae] dari artis debut tahun lalu, kalian jadi pemenang rookie award terbanyak. Ada pidato penerimaan
[Stella] that you haven't done? I think we've done them all, but still
[Stella] yang belum disampaikan? Kayaknya udah semua sih tapi tetap
[Stella] We were so so honored, and something we always talked about since before our debut was that we must
[Stella] Kami sangat sangat tersanjung, dan sejak sebelum debut kami selalu bilang kita harus
[Stella] win the Rookie Award, and we ended up winning nine, so thank you so so much.
[Stella] menang Rookie Award, dan ternyata kami dapat sembilan, jadi terima kasih banyak sekali.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, rookie award hunter group, a group with great potential
[Bae Seongjae] Ya rookie award hunter group, grup yang punya kemampuan
[Bae Seongjae] Finally, can one of you do an acrostic poem with your fandom name S2U for promotion?
[Bae Seongjae] Terakhir, salah satu wakil puisi akrostik nama fandom S2U untuk promosi bisa? Eh
[Stella] Yuha's good at acrostic poems.
[Stella] Yuha jago. Puisi akrostik.
[Bae Seongjae] Immediately passing it off
[Bae Seongjae] Langsung lempar
[Bae Seongjae] Let's go, 'S'
[Bae Seongjae] Ayo 하
[Yuha] Hearts2Hearts' RUDE
[Yuha] Hearts2Hearts RUDE
[Bae Seongjae] 'U'
[Bae Seongjae] 추
[Yuha] I recommend it.
[Yuha] Aku rekomendasikan.
[Yuha] Wow, nice
[Yuha] Wah keren
[Bae Seongjae] Good.
[Bae Seongjae] Bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Alright, we've done this blatant promo time. Now it's time for
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, tadi kita udah lakuin promosi terang-terangan. Sekarang kita ke keyword talk time
[Bae Seongjae] keyword talk time. We're introducing keywords for Hearts2Hearts and Yuha and Stella.
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Namanya HAKISO - Hearts2Hearts dan keyword Yuha Stella akan diperkenalkan.
[Staff] Woo
[Staff] Woo
[Bae Seongjae] So the first keyword is SM. Yes. Hearts2Hearts, SM Entertainment's youngest girl group
[Bae Seongjae] Nah keyword pertama adalah SM. Ya. Grup girl paling muda SM Entertainment
[Bae Seongjae] and I'm from the same company too.
[Bae Seongjae] Hearts2Hearts, dan aku juga dari perusahaan yang sama.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, I was trying to sort out the seniority here, but I'm actually
[Bae Seongjae] Eh aku mau sorting nomor induk sedikit, aku ternyata junior
[Bae Seongjae] a whole 7 years junior to Yuha in terms of joining the company. Yes. And to Stella
[Bae Seongjae] 7 tahun dari Yuha. Ya. Stella
[Bae Seongjae] about 2 years junior. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] sekitar 2 tahun lebih junior. Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] So it feels like a junior is hosting right now. Yes. Someone said bow your head,
[Bae Seongjae] Jadi sekarang rasanya kayak junior yang jadi MC. Ya. Ada yang bilang bow,
[Bae Seongjae] someone said 'good', someone said bow
[Bae Seongjae] ada yang bilang joa-i,
[Bae Seongjae] in greeting
[Bae Seongjae] ada yang bilang hormat dulu
[Bae Seongjae] Uh Yuha, you got cast by SM three times?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh Yuha, kamu di-casting SM sampai tiga kali ya?
[Yuha] Uh that's right.
[Yuha] Eh betul.
[Bae Seongjae] On the street? Yes
[Bae Seongjae] Di jalan? Ya
[Yuha] All three times on the street
[Yuha] Tiga kali semua di jalan
[Bae Seongjae] Uh where was it? I heard earlier that you were ten
[Bae Seongjae] Eh dimana ya, tadi denger umur sepuluh
[Bae Seongjae] years old, so was it at school or? Yes
[Bae Seongjae] tahun, itu gimana, di sekolah? Atau ya
[Yuha] My hometown is Wonju, Gangwon Province
[Yuha] Rumah asli saya di Wonju, Gangwon
[Yuha] I got cast once in front of my elementary school when I was in 4th grade
[Yuha] Waktu SD kelas 4 di-casting sekali di depan sekolah
[Yuha] Then I transferred schools when I came to Seoul for trainee life, and got cast again in front of that middle school
[Yuha] Terus sekarang ke Seoul buat jadi trainee, pindah sekolah, di depan SMP lagi
[Yuha] and
[Yuha] di-casting
[Yuha] the last time was when I went to the dentist
[Yuha] Terakhir ke dokter gigi terus di-casting
[Bae Seongjae] I see. At the dentist, in the waiting room together
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Dokter gigi itu bareng di ruang tunggu
[Yuha] In the dentist's elevator
[Yuha] Di lift dokter gigi
[Yuha] Amazing
[Yuha] Gila
[Bae Seongjae] Ah in the elevator, like 'oh what a pretty kid' or something
[Bae Seongjae] Ah di lift, eh 'wah ada anak cakep nih' gitu ya
[Bae Seongjae] Oh I see. Someone's asking if it's because your teeth are so straight.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh begitu. Ada yang tanya apa karena giginya rapi.
[Bae Seongjae] They say SM staff are always out scouting
[Bae Seongjae] Staff SM emang keliling mulu katanya
[Bae Seongjae] But managers probably always think like that.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh tapi manager-manager pasti selalu mikir gitu kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] Like 'oh there's a good person, there's a good kid.' Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh ada orang bagus, ada anak bagus nih. Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] It wasn't the same manager who cast you, right? [Yuha] Uh, they were all different people I think.
[Bae Seongjae] Bukan manager yang sama yang nge-casting kan? [Yuha] Eh, kayaknya semua orang beda.
[Bae Seongjae] It's not like they kept persistently coming back after you rejected them, then following you to the dentist
[Bae Seongjae] Bukan kayak samgo chorye yang dateng terus ditolak terus dateng lagi sampai dokter gigi
[Bae Seongjae] but different people each time, yes.
[Bae Seongjae] ikutin gitu, tapi masing-masing orang beda ya,
[Bae Seongjae] Stella
[Bae Seongjae] Stella
[Bae Seongjae] you
[Bae Seongjae] ya,
[Bae Seongjae] auditioned at an academy
[Bae Seongjae] audisi academy ya
[Stella] That's right.
[Stella] Betul.
[Bae Seongjae] You got cast by 32 companies?
[Bae Seongjae] Sampai 32 perusahaan nge-casting kamu?
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Wow, 32 companies is like
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Wah 32 itu hampir kayak
[Bae Seongjae] being drafted by all 32 teams in Major League Baseball, but you chose
[Bae Seongjae] baseball Major League Amerika yang 32 tim draft gitu rasanya, terus pilih
[Bae Seongjae] SM out of them? Yes, yes, that's right.
[Bae Seongjae] SM ya? Ya ya, betul.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, what was your reason for choosing them?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, alasan pilihnya
[Stella] Well, first I got
[Stella] Yang paling pertama itu aku
[Stella] cast by the company and then I wanted to audition for 2nd and 3rd rounds at companies
[Stella] di-casting sama perusahaan terus aku mau ikut audisi kedua ketiga di perusahaan yang
[Stella] that I was interested, but SM contacted me first with the acceptance news
[Stella] Nah yang pertama kali hubungin aku itu SM dengan kabar kelulusan
[Stella] So I thought, ah, this is fate. I wanted to join SM anyway, and they
[Stella] Jadi aku mikir, ah ini takdir. Kan aku emang udah pengen masuk SM, dan mereka yang pertama
[Stella] contacted me first
[Stella] hubungin aku
[Bae Seongjae] I'm thinking of making you do a World Cup tournament. So let me set up a bracket for the round of 32
[Bae Seongjae] Masuknya harus lewat World Cup ya. Oke kalau gitu aku bikin bracket 32 besar dulu
[Bae Seongjae] I'll make one for you, so let's try a World Cup where you appeal to me. Make it to at least the semi-finals. Something like
[Bae Seongjae] Aku kasih, jadi kalian appeal ke aku buat World Cup. Minimal sampai semifinal ya. Begitu
[Bae Seongjae] that
[Bae Seongjae] kah?
[Stella] It wasn't like that, I just really love SM's senior artists
[Stella] Bukan gitu sih, aku tuh suka banget sama sunbae-sunbae SM
[Bae Seongjae] Ah wow, that's almost like real major
[Bae Seongjae] Ah wah ini mah udah level Major
[Bae Seongjae] league level, like Ohtani class. Yes, it really was 32 teams.
[Bae Seongjae] League, kayak Ohtani ya. Wah beneran 32 besar.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, that's one more than Baskin-Robbins flavors, right? Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh angkanya lebih banyak satu dari es krim ya? Benar? Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Sorry about that.
[Bae Seongjae] Maaf.
[Stella] No, it's fine.
[Stella] Gak apa-apa kok.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Now, could you brag about your agency SM for us?
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Nah, coba banggain agensi SM kalian
[Yuha] Oh
[Yuha] Oh
[Yuha] Wow
[Yuha] Wah
[Yuha] There's so much to brag about.
[Yuha] Yang bisa dibanggain tuh banyak banget.
[Yuha] So much.
[Yuha] Banyak banget.
[Yuha] Because our company loyalty is incredible
[Yuha] Soalnya aku cinta banget sama perusahaan
[Yuha] First
[Yuha] Pertama
[Stella] First, our senior artists
[Stella] Pertama sunbae-sunbae
[Stella] Our senior artists that we really respect and think are amazing
[Stella] Sunbae-sunbae yang kita hormati dan kita anggap luar biasa
[Stella] Who are they all
[Stella] Siapa aja semua
[Bae Seongjae] It's hard to mention them all, right? Yes. Among them, if there's someone you've met recently
[Bae Seongjae] Susah nyebutin semua ya. Iya. Di antara mereka, yang baru-baru ini ketemu
[Bae Seongjae] for the sake of the senior artists
[Bae Seongjae] ada gak sunbae-sunbae buat kalian?
[Yuha] Recently, Kim Heechul sunbae helped us a lot during variety show filming
[Yuha] Baru-baru ini Kim Heechul sunbaenim banyak banget bantuin waktu syuting variety show
[Bae Seongjae] We were so grateful. Oh, how did he help you?
[Bae Seongjae] Makasih banget. Oh bantuin apa?
[Stella] Uh, he joked around a lot and talked to us
[Stella] Eh dia seru banget, banyak bercanda sama kita dan ngajak ngobrol
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, it's a bit hard to spoil which program yet
[Bae Seongjae] Ah programnya masih agak spoiler sih
[Yuha] Ah, but the article already came out - it's Knowing Bros
[Yuha] Ah tapi udah keluar beritanya kok, Knowing Brothers
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, you appeared on Knowing Bros. Ah, yes
[Bae Seongjae] Ah kalian ke Knowing Bros ya. Ah iya
[Bae Seongjae] Is there any song by SM senior artists that
[Bae Seongjae] Si Dark Die 96 ini, ada lagu sunbae SM
[Bae Seongjae] you'd like to cover? Uh
[Bae Seongjae] yang pengen di-cover gak? Eh
[Stella] Actually, we recently covered f(x) sunbae's Electric Shock at our fan meeting
[Stella] Sebenernya kita baru-baru ini di fan meeting cover lagu f(x) sunbaenim Electric Shock
[Stella] I've always wanted to do it since my trainee days, so it already had this kind of feeling
[Stella] Aku dari jaman trainee udah pengen banget nyanyiin itu, jadi udah kayak gini rasanya
[Bae Seongjae] It's a masterpiece.
[Bae Seongjae] Lagu legendaris ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, so you call it Electric Shock.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh Electric Shock ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. I used to call it Electric Shock
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Aku tadinya bilang Electric Shock sih
[Staff] Ah, yes.
[Staff] Ah, iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, between this and Shock, something like this at the end
[Bae Seongjae] Ah ini Shock sama yang belakang
[Bae Seongjae] if you remove that, it sounds kind of cool. Ah,
[Bae Seongjae] harus dibuang biar keren. Ah,
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, you recently had an SMTOWN concert. Uh, what was the most memorable moment?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, baru-baru ini ada konser SMTOWN ya, momen yang paling berkesan kapan?
[Stella] Uh, when do you remember? For me
[Stella] Eh, kamu inget kapan? Aku
[Stella] recently when I got to perform on stage with
[Stella] Baru-baru ini bareng Hyoyeon Girls' Generation sunbaenim
[Stella] Girls' Generation's Hyoyeon sunbae, that was probably the most memorable for me. I see.
[Stella] manggung bareng, waktu itu yang paling membahagiakan kayaknya. Begitu ya.
[Stella] Being able to perform together with such a senior
[Stella] Soalnya bisa bareng-bareng naik panggung sama sunbae senior
[Stella] I was so nervous but they were so kind to me, so it's a really happy memory.
[Stella] jadi deg-degan banget tapi sunbae-nya baik banget jadi bahagia banget ingetnya.
[Bae Seongjae] You were born in '07, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Kalian kelahiran 2007 kan ya?
[Stella] Yes, that's right.
[Stella] Ya. Betul.
[Bae Seongjae] In a way, you were born around when Girls' Generation was just starting their activities. Wow
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau dipikir-pikir, kalian lahir waktu Girls' Generation baru mulai aktif ya. Wah
[Bae Seongjae] That must really be overwhelming.
[Bae Seongjae] Pasti terharu banget ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Any company seniors you've gotten close to? Someone you can say you're friends with?
[Bae Seongjae] Sunbae di agensi yang udah akrab gimana. Yang bisa dibilang akrab sama kalian.
[Speaker] Mm.
[Speaker] Mm.
[Yuha] Oh, Hyoyeon sunbaenim who we're close with.
[Yuha] Eh, Hyoyeon sunbae yang akrab.
[Stella] Hyoyeon sunbaenim. Yes. Kim Heechul sunbaenim.
[Stella] Hyoyeon sunbae. Ya. Kim Heechul sunbae.
[Stella] Heechul sunbaenim
[Stella] Heechul sunbae
[Bae Seongjae] Those are the ones you can mention since you recently worked together.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya, karena baru-baru ini bareng ngapain gitu jadi masih oke lah nyebutnya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, next search term. '07-liners.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, kata kunci selanjutnya. '07-liners.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. Ah, you two became adults this year,
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. Ah, kalian berdua tahun ini jadi dewasa
[Bae Seongjae] Born in 2007, '07-liner friends.
[Bae Seongjae] kelahiran 2007, '07-liners yang seumuran.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, Park Gyeong-dong said the '07-liners became adults and finally went to PC rooms at night
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, Park Kyungdong bilang '07-liners udah dewasa dan akhirnya bisa ke PC bang malam hari
[Bae Seongjae] Is there anything you want to try together as adults?
[Bae Seongjae] sebagai orang dewasa, ada yang pengen dicoba bareng-bareng?
[Yuha] Oh, I want to try getting my driver's license.
[Yuha] Eh, pengen ambil SIM mobil.
[Bae Seongjae] License already? Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] SIM? Udah? Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, you want to get it quickly so you can drive somewhere on trips and stuff like that?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, pengen cepet-cepet ambil terus nyetir ke mana gitu, traveling atau gimana?
[Yuha] Yes. Even if I get my license, I probably won't have time, but still
[Yuha] Ya. Tapi kayaknya walau udah dapet SIM juga bakal ga ada waktu sih, tapi
[Yuha] I can get it when I turn 20, so I want to try
[Yuha] Kalau sudah 20 tahun bisa dapat, jadi mau coba
[Bae Seongjae] Since you can get the qualification then.
[Bae Seongjae] Karena bisa dapat lisensinya kan.
[Bae Seongjae] Anything else? Like maybe trying beer for the first time or something?
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang lain ga? Yang pengen coba minum atau apa gitu
[Stella] That too, someday going to Han River and eating ramen there
[Stella] Itu juga, kapan-kapan pengen ke Han River makan ramyeon
[Bae Seongjae] Eating ramen, that's great.
[Bae Seongjae] Makan ramyeon, bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Lucky 110 asks, "In your teens, is there something you'd want to say to your 20-year-old self"
[Bae Seongjae] Lucky 110 tanya, dari masa remaja ke diriku yang 20 tahun, ada pesan
[Bae Seongjae] something to say.
[Bae Seongjae] yang mau disampaikan?
[Speaker] Mm
[Speaker] Mm
[Bae Seongjae] Shouldn't it be the other way around? If your 20-year-old self has something to say to your teenage self
[Bae Seongjae] Kebalik ya? Harusnya dari yang 20 tahun ke masa remajaku
[Bae Seongjae] To your younger self
[Bae Seongjae] ke masa kecilku
[Yuha] Well, it wasn't that long ago, but
[Yuha] Walaupun belum lama sih
[Yuha] Play more, have more fun
[Yuha] main lebih banyak lagi, main lebih banyak
[Yuha] Enjoy more
[Yuha] nikmatin lebih banyak
[Bae Seongjae] Was there something you couldn't enjoy?
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang ga sempet dinikmati ya?
[Yuha] Oh, that's
[Yuha] Eh, bukan itu
[Yuha] not it
[Yuha] bukan itu
[Yuha] That's not it, but just have more fun
[Yuha] bukan itu tapi main lebih bebas aja
[Bae Seongjae] In the chat someone said 'you made it,' someone said buy stocks
[Bae Seongjae] Di chat ada yang bilang 'kamu sukses', ada yang bilang beli saham
[Bae Seongjae] Someone said since you'll practice like crazy later,
[Bae Seongjae] ada yang bilang main aja dulu soalnya nanti bakal latihan mati-matian
[Bae Seongjae] play while you can. Ah, that's true. Once you enter the company, you have to practice incredibly hard
[Bae Seongjae] Ah iya ya. Nanti kalau udah masuk agensi dari situ harus latihan keras banget
[Bae Seongjae] from then on.
[Bae Seongjae] kan.
[Bae Seongjae] You'll win nine rookie awards, so prepare your acceptance speech in advance. Oh.
[Bae Seongjae] Kalian bakal dapet 9 rookie award jadi siapin pidato penerimaan penghargaan. Eh.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, you two are the same age but have completely opposite MBTIs.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, kalian berdua umurnya sama tapi MBTI-nya kebalikan banget ya.
[Yuha] Yes. That's right. Exactly.
[Yuha] Ya. Bener. Betul.
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha, you're
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha kamu
[Yuha] INTJ.
[Yuha] INTJ.
[Bae Seongjae] INTJ. And Stella, you're
[Bae Seongjae] INTJ. Stella kamu
[Yuha] I'm ENFP.
[Yuha] Aku ENFP.
[Bae Seongjae] ENFP. Yes. Have you ever felt like "wow, we're really different"
[Bae Seongjae] ENFP. Ya. Jadi kalau lagi jalan bareng gitu, pernah ngerasa "ah, beda banget ya" gitu
[Bae Seongjae] when hanging out together?
[Bae Seongjae] nggak?
[Yuha] With Stella, I don't really think we're that different, but
[Yuha] Stella sih kayaknya nggak terlalu beda-beda amat tapi agak
[Yuha] that's right.
[Yuha] bener sih.
[Yuha] Oh, how should I put it? She seems to have a bit of a fiery personality. Her style is, ah,
[Yuha] Ah, gimana ya? Kayaknya ada sifat temperamental dikit. Stella itu ah,
[Bae Seongjae] Planning
[Bae Seongjae] planning
[Yuha] kind of impulsive, like
[Yuha] agak spontan gitu
[Yuha] "Let's go buy this," or "Let's go eat that." She really likes that kind of thing, and I really like planning things
[Yuha] "yuk beli ini", "yuk makan itu". Suka banget yang kayak gitu dan aku lebih suka bikin rencana
[Yuha] so that's kind of different.
[Yuha] jadi itu yang agak beda.
[Bae Seongjae] You're both N types, and Yuha, are you more on the I side? Yes. It seems like
[Bae Seongjae] Kalian berdua sama-sama N dan Yuha kamu cenderung I ya? Ya. Kayak fifty-fifty gitu
[Yuha] it's half and half, but still more I
[Yuha] sih tapi tetep I
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, Stella, are you definitely E? That's right.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah Stella kamu yakin banget E ya? Betul.
[Bae Seongjae] Are you T, Yuha? Yes
[Bae Seongjae] T ya Yuha? Ya
[Yuha] I'm T.
[Yuha] T kok.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, so when you're talking, there are
[Bae Seongjae] Ah jadi kalau ngobrol kadang agak
[Bae Seongjae] still some cold moments sometimes? Right
[Bae Seongjae] tetep ada momen dingin juga nggak? Gitu
[Stella] Sometimes
[Stella] Kadang
[Stella] But even though Yuha is totally T,
[Stella] Tapi ah Yuha emang banget T sih tapi
[Stella] she's really emotional and sensitive.
[Stella] perasaannya kaya banget loh.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, but still calm and composed, right.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah tetep tenang dan gitu ya.
[Stella] So she empathizes well too, and I've never really felt like she's super T. And Stella, are you perfectly
[Stella] Makanya empatinya bagus banget dan aku nggak pernah ngerasa dia terlalu T gitu. Sampai sekarang Stella kamu perfect
[Yuha] F? Uh, but I'm not perfectly either, sometimes
[Yuha] F ya? Eh tapi juga nggak perfect banget kadang
[Bae Seongjae] she shows that side. Oh, sometimes like that. You both have a lot of half-and-half traits. Yes, yes
[Bae Seongjae] "ah kadang gitu ya" fifty-fifty banyak ya. Kalian berdua ya ya
[Bae Seongjae] Do you two '07-liners ever bicker about things like menu choices or something?
[Bae Seongjae] Sesama 07-liners pernah ribut nggak? Kayak milih menu atau apa gitu
[Stella] But I feel like Haram and Yuha and I have never had any really big
[Stella] Tapi aku sama Haram Yuha kayaknya nggak pernah ribut besar-besaran
[Stella] fights. Yes.
[Stella] sih. Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Opposite personality types surprisingly don't fight much. I see.
[Bae Seongjae] Kepribadian yang berlawanan ternyata jarang ribut ya. Begitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Now, the next keyword is piano, which is Yuha's keyword. You're a famous piano prodigy who's been playing since age six.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Nah, keyword selanjutnya piano, ini keyword Yuha. Umur 6 tahun
[Bae Seongjae] who's been playing piano since age six.
[Bae Seongjae] udah main piano, pianis muda terkenal.
[Yuha] Mm.
[Yuha] Mm.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, how good were you?
[Bae Seongjae] Wah, seberapa jago sih?
[Yuha] Uh, I competed in competitions every year to some extent
[Yuha] Eh, lumayan ikut kompetisi setiap tahun
[Bae Seongjae] Cool.
[Bae Seongjae] Concours?
[Yuha] Yes. From first grade in elementary school until about second, third grade in middle school
[Yuha] Ya. Dari SD kelas 1 sampai SMP kelas 2, kelas 3
[Yuha] I competed every year and
[Yuha] ikut setiap tahun dan selalu
[Yuha] I think I always placed in the top rankings.
[Yuha] masuk ranking kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] I see here, Chuncheon City National Music Competition Piano Division Elementary 1st Place.
[Bae Seongjae] Liat nih Concours Musik Nasional Chuncheon divisi piano SD juara 1.
[Staff] Mm.
[Staff] Mm.
[Bae Seongjae] Multiple piano competition awards in elementary school. Wow. But that piano performance
[Bae Seongjae] Banyak banget penghargaan concours piano waktu SD. Wah. Terus main piano
[Bae Seongjae] video and there's this comment.
[Bae Seongjae] piano dia, dan ada komentarnya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, someone named Potato F4 said they went to the same school and there was always 'Grand Prize Winner Yu Haram'
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang 'Gamja F4' satu sekolah sama dia, katanya di depan les piano selalu ada
[Bae Seongjae] posted in front of the piano academy.
[Bae Seongjae] tulisan 'Juara Besar: Yuha Ram'.
[Staff] Wow
[Staff] Wah
[Bae Seongjae] So when they heard you were debuting, they were like 'Oh, that kid who plays piano really well.'
[Bae Seongjae] Jadi waktu denger dia debut, langsung 'Oh, si anak yang jago piano itu'.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh
[Bae Seongjae] Ya
[Bae Seongjae] Right. Since your real name is Yu Haram. That's right.
[Bae Seongjae] Betul. Nama aslinya Yuha Ram. Begitu.
[Bae Seongjae] And someone said you seem to play the best among all the idols who claim to play piano.
[Bae Seongjae] Dan katanya dari idol yang bilang bisa piano, dia paling jago.
[Stella] Oh right. She plays really well.
[Stella] Ah betul. Dia bener-bener jago.
[Bae Seongjae] Have you seen her play? [Stella] I saw her once during trainee days and she played so
[Bae Seongjae] Kamu pernah liat dia main? [Stella] Waktu trainee pernah liat sekali, bener-bener
[Stella] well. I was really surprised.
[Stella] jago banget. Sampe aku kaget.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, did you ever think like, while playing piano, that you'd
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, jadi pernah kepikiran gak sih waktu main piano 'nanti aku
[Bae Seongjae] become a pianist later on?
[Bae Seongjae] jadi pianis aja' gitu?
[Yuha] Yes. Originally my dream was to be a pianist, so I was preparing for arts high school entrance exams and stuff,
[Yuha] Ya. Dulu emang cita-citanya jadi pianis, sampe mau persiapan masuk
[Yuha] but after joining the company
[Yuha] sekolah seni gitu, tapi setelah masuk company
[Yuha] I started thinking I should become an idol instead
[Yuha] mikir 'kayaknya jadi idol aja deh'
[Yuha] and here I am.
[Yuha] jadinya begini.
[Bae Seongjae] Do you sometimes keep playing the keyboard so your skills don't get rusty?
[Bae Seongjae] Sesekali masih main keyboard biar gak berkarat?
[Yuha] Yes. Sometimes when I'm stressed, I play piano alone at the company.
[Yuha] Ya. Kadang buat buang stress main piano sendiri di company.
[Yuha] But I'm not as good as I used to be.
[Yuha] Tapi udah gak sebagus dulu.
[Bae Seongjae] Are you thinking about composing or anything like that later on?
[Bae Seongjae] Nanti ada rencana nyoba bikin lagu gitu?
[Yuha] Oh. Yes. I really want to try composing and stuff.
[Yuha] Ah ya. Pengen banget nyoba bikin lagu.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. People ask what you've been doing instead of preparing piano for 'Ten', and you play piano to relieve stress.
[Bae Seongjae] Daripada nanya 'kenapa gak latihan piano', lebih baik main piano buat
[Bae Seongjae] That's really good.
[Bae Seongjae] buang stress. Bagus itu.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, the next search term is Canada
[Bae Seongjae] Oke, keyword selanjutnya adalah Kanada
[Stella] Uh-oh. Mm.
[Stella] Ah hehe. Hmm.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, this is Stella's keyword
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, ini keyword Stella
[Bae Seongjae] Yes, when you were about five years old
[Bae Seongjae] Ya, umur sekitar 5 tahun
[Bae Seongjae] you immigrated to Vancouver, Canada
[Bae Seongjae] pindah ke Vancouver, Kanada
[Stella] Yes, that's right.
[Stella] Ya, betul.
[Bae Seongjae] and then came back to Korea, to Busan.
[Bae Seongjae] terus balik lagi ke Busan, Korea. Reverse immigration gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] So you're definitely in charge of English for Hearts2Hearts?
[Bae Seongjae] Di Hearts2Hearts, yang jadi PIC bahasa Inggris pasti kamu dong
[Stella] Ah, that's right.
[Stella] Ah, betul.
[Bae Seongjae] Is English more comfortable for you, or Korean?
[Bae Seongjae] Bahasa Inggris atau Korea, mana yang lebih nyaman?
[Stella] I think English is still more comfortable for me.
[Stella] Sampe sekarang kayaknya bahasa Inggris yang lebih nyaman.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, I see. So you dream in English too. Then
[Bae Seongjae] Oh gitu. Berarti mimpi juga pake bahasa Inggris. Terus kalo
[Bae Seongjae] when you talk with your parents
[Bae Seongjae] ngobrol sama orang tua gimana?
[Stella] Uh, when we lived in Canada we mixed both languages, but now that we're back in Korea
[Stella] Waktu di Kanada campur-campur, tapi sekarang udah balik ke Korea
[Stella] we mainly speak Korean now.
[Stella] jadi sekarang lebih sering pake Korea.
[Bae Seongjae] Hey, then, what do you call it, in Canada it's hockey right? Ice hockey.
[Bae Seongjae] Wah kalo Kanada kan hoki es tuh. Ice hockey.
[Stella] That's right.
[Stella] Betul.
[Bae Seongjae] Did you watch ice hockey and stuff?
[Bae Seongjae] Pernah nonton ice hockey juga?
[Stella] Not really. [Bae Seongjae] That's too bad. Yeah.
[Stella] Gak sih. [Bae Seongjae] Wah sayang banget. Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] I recently watched ice hockey during the Winter Olympics
[Bae Seongjae] Ice hockey aku kemarin-kemarin liat di Olimpiade Musim Dingin
[Bae Seongjae] finals match between Canada and the US.
[Bae Seongjae] final Olimpiade Musim Dingin Kanada vs Amerika.
[Stella] Oh really? Ah,
[Stella] Ah beneran? Ah,
[Bae Seongjae] Our Canadian girl, that match
[Bae Seongjae] Anak Kanada itu pertandingan
[Stella] Do you like ice hockey?
[Stella] Suka ice hockey?
[Stella] I'm gonna start liking ice hockey now. Yeah. I'll wear ice hockey clothes.
[Stella] Ice hockey mulai sekarang mau suka nih. Iya. Mau pakai baju ice hockey.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] If you want me to stop talking about stuff you're not curious about,
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau bilang jangan cerita yang nggak ditanya
[Bae Seongjae] just say you're sick of it. Yeah.
[Bae Seongjae] kalau bosen bilang aja ya. Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] So you're from Canada, but your hometown is Ulsan and your parents live in Busan.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, asli Kanada tapi kampung halaman Ulsan, orang tua tinggal di Busan.
[Bae Seongjae] So you sometimes slip into dialect.
[Bae Seongjae] Makanya logat kadang keluar katanya.
[Stella] Yeah, that's right.
[Stella] Eh, bener.
[Stella] Yeah. It comes out without me knowing and the members always tease me like, "Why'd you
[Stella] Eh. Tanpa sadar keluar gitu, member-member selalu eh, kenapa kamu pakai logat
[Stella] use dialect?" I remember that.
[Stella] tadi? Gitu ngatain, inget banget.
[Bae Seongjae] What kind of dialect slips out sometimes? The ones you use often.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh. Apa apa yang kadang keluar gitu? Logat yang sering dipake.
[Stella] But I don't even realize it's coming out
[Stella] Tapi aku juga agak tanpa sadar keluar soalnya
[Bae Seongjae] Uh
[Bae Seongjae] Eh
[Stella] We have YE-ON who's from Yangsan, our youngest, and when I talk with
[Stella] Sekarang kita ada YE-ON dari Yangsan, si maknae, kalau ngobrol sama YE-ON
[Stella] her, the dialect comes out a lot.
[Stella] sering keluar logat kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, so it slips out when you meet someone from the same region. Yeah
[Bae Seongjae] Ah malah ketika ketemu orang sesama daerah langsung keluar ya. Eh
[Bae Seongjae] Can you say something? From the Yeongnam region?
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bisa satu kata? Logat daerah Yeongnam
[Bae Seongjae] Got anything you're confident with? [Stella] Unni, oppa, I love you.
[Bae Seongjae] yang pede? [Stella] Eonni oppa-ya saranghan-de.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] Eh,
[Bae Seongjae] It came right out. And since you speak English well, you got the English narration
[Bae Seongjae] Langsung keluar ya. Dan bahasa Inggris juga jago makanya di RUDE ini dapet bagian narasi Inggris
[Bae Seongjae] killing part in RUDE, and everyone's going crazy saying it's super cute and cool.
[Bae Seongjae] killing part yang lucu dan keren banget sampai heboh.
[Bae Seongjae] Could you do that narration
[Bae Seongjae] Bisa nggak tanpa musik bagian narasi
[Staff] Oh
[Staff] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] part a cappella?
[Bae Seongjae] ini?
[Staff] Of course.
[Staff] Tentu dong.
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. I watched the music video earlier and how should I put it? The feeling was really
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Tadi juga udah liat MV-nya, gimana ya bilangnya? Feel-nya tuh beda
[Bae Seongjae] special.
[Bae Seongjae] banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Could we hear it?
[Bae Seongjae] Bisa liat sekali?
[Stella] Yes. You know what he said to me? He was
[Stella] Iya. You know what he said to me? He was
[Stella] like, "You're so rude." And I was like,
[Stella] like, "You're so rude." And I was like,
[Stella] couldn't even
[Stella] couldn't even
[Bae Seongjae] Sounds like something from Disney or American TV shows with
[Bae Seongjae] Disney kayak pernah liat dan drama Amerika
[Bae Seongjae] teenage girls. Thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] remaja perempuan gitu vibesnya makasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Could we try switching parts?
[Bae Seongjae] Gantian bisa?
[Yuha] Oh, let's see. I'll try it. I think I'll do well.
[Yuha] Oh, ayo. Coba ah. Pasti bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Can you do it? I'll try the narration part.
[Bae Seongjae] Bisa? Bagian narasi coba.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh.
[Yuha] You know what he said to me? What?
[Yuha] You know what he said to me? What?
[Yuha] He was like, "You're so rude." And I was like, "Bo, does it
[Yuha] He was like, "You're so rude." And I was like, "Bo, does it
[Yuha] look like I could care? I couldn't even care."
[Yuha] look like I could care? I couldn't even care."
[Bae Seongjae] Wow,
[Bae Seongjae] Wah,
[Bae Seongjae] Someone said it got rustic.
[Bae Seongjae] ada yang bilang jadi lebih hangat rasanya.
[Staff] So Korean
[Staff] Terlalu kayak orang Korea
[Bae Seongjae] Cute. They said now they can understand you. Oh, but you're really good at it too, Yuha.
[Bae Seongjae] Lucu. Sekarang bisa dimengerti katanya. Eh, tapi bagus banget. Yuha juga.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Great. Truly a global group.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Bagus. Memang grup global.
[Bae Seongjae] Okay, so our time is almost up for Part 1,
[Bae Seongjae] Nah. Jadi, waktu kita udah hampir selesai part 1
[Bae Seongjae] so we'll come back in Part 2 and chat with you two again.
[Bae Seongjae] kita balik lagi di part 2 buat ngobrol sama kalian berdua.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Not too hard, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Gak terlalu susah kan?
[Stella] It's so fun.
[Stella] Seru banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Time flies, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Waktu cepet ya?
[Stella] Yeah.
[Stella] Ya.
[Staff] Did you go to an English kindergarten?
[Staff] Lulusan TK Inggris ya?
[Yuha] Huh?
[Yuha] Hah?
[Yuha] Oh, no.
[Yuha] Oh, bukan.
[Staff] Then why are you so good at it?
[Staff] Bukan tapi kok jago?
[Stella] Yeah. But she's really good at English.
[Stella] Ya. Tapi dia jago banget bahasa Inggris.
[Bae Seongjae] Exactly
[Bae Seongjae] Makanya
[Stella] She's really good with languages
[Stella] Jago banget sama bahasa
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, but that pronunciation is almost native-level, really
[Bae Seongjae] Wah tapi pelafalan asli hampir beneran
[Bae Seongjae] Really like a teenage girl from American TV shows
[Bae Seongjae] beneran persis kayak remaja cewek di drama Amerika
[Yuha] Thank you.
[Yuha] Terima kasih.
[Yuha] So you watched that? [Bae Seongjae] Oh, this is something I ordered from overseas myself
[Yuha] Ini kalian liat itu ya? [Bae Seongjae] Ah ini saya beli sendiri dari luar negeri
[Bae Seongjae] It's ice hockey gear.
[Bae Seongjae] peralatan ice hockey.
[Yuha] This team exists
[Yuha] Ada tim ini
[Bae Seongjae] This is that Minnesota... Minneso... yeah
[Bae Seongjae] Ini itu Minnesota Minnesera ya
[Stella] Oh you're doing well, Minnesota
[Stella] Eh bagus tapi Minnesota
[Bae Seongjae] Kind of oh
[Bae Seongjae] Agak oh
[Bae Seongjae] This was a unique gesture, oh
[Bae Seongjae] Ini gesture aneh tapi oh
[Stella] No no
[Stella] Bukan bukan
[Bae Seongjae] Uh
[Bae Seongjae] Eh
[Stella] Oh you look cool
[Stella] Eh keren
[Bae Seongjae] Thank you
[Bae Seongjae] Terima kasih
[Bae Seongjae] Uh Vancouver, so when did you move there? [Stella] Me, in 2013
[Bae Seongjae] Eh Vancouver kapan pindahnya? [Stella] Saya tahun 2013
[Stella] I went when I was five
[Stella] umur 5 tahun pindah
[Stella] lived there for 11 years then came back to Korea
[Stella] tinggal 11 tahun terus balik lagi ke Korea
[Bae Seongjae] Vancouver, I went there first. I went in 2010 to cover the Winter Olympics
[Bae Seongjae] Vancouver saya duluan kesana. Saya 2010 buat liputan Olimpiade Musim Dingin
[Bae Seongjae] Hmm
[Bae Seongjae] Hmm
[Bae Seongjae] Strange sense of competition
[Bae Seongjae] Rasa bersaing aneh
[Stella] Oh this is all being heard, right? Yeah.
[Stella] Ah ini kedengeran semua ya? Ya.
[Stella] Ah. Uh. Hello.
[Stella] Ah. Eh. Halo.
[Bae Seongjae] Hmm. Are you telling the junior to bow down? Yeah. Being
[Bae Seongjae] Hmm. Suruh junior sungkem ya? Ya. Enak
[Bae Seongjae] old is nice, they say.
[Bae Seongjae] jadi orang tua katanya.
[Bae Seongjae] Everyone, you're now with Bae Seongjae's TEN, with the lively and bold girl group
[Bae Seongjae] Kalian sekarang di Bae Seongjae's TEN bareng grup ceria dan berani
[Bae Seongjae] Hearts2Hearts' '07-liners Yuha and Stella, the Nutella duo, who came back with their new song RUDE!
[Bae Seongjae] Hearts2Hearts yang comeback dengan lagu baru RUDE!, 07-liners Yuha Stella gabungan jadi Nutella duo
[Bae Seongjae] We were doing keyword talk. Yeah. This time's keyword is
[Bae Seongjae] lagi bareng kita. Kita lagi ngobrol keyword talk. Ya. Keyword kali ini
[Bae Seongjae] all-rounder. It's Yuha's keyword - she's a hexagon player all-rounder member who's good at dancing, singing, broadcasting, everything.
[Bae Seongjae] all-rounder. Ini keywordnya Yuha, soalnya dia member hexagon player all-rounder yang jago dance, nyanyi, broadcasting semua
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, besides dancing and singing, you're really good at
[Bae Seongjae] kan. Eh selain dance sama nyanyi, ternyata kamu jago
[Bae Seongjae] so many other things. What else
[Bae Seongjae] banyak banget hal lain. Apa lagi
[Bae Seongjae] are you good at? [Yuha] I'm really good at mental math.
[Bae Seongjae] yang kamu jago? [Yuha] Aku eh jago hitung cepat di kepala.
[Bae Seongjae] Mental math?
[Bae Seongjae] Hitung di kepala?
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. Uh, then what's 78 times 56?
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Eh kalau gitu 78 kali 56
[Yuha] Ah, I can't do stuff like that [Bae Seongjae] Then what about addition?
[Yuha] Ah yang kayak gini gabisa [Bae Seongjae] Kalau tambahan gimana?
[Yuha] I look at license plates
[Yuha] Aku tuh liat plat nomor mobil
[Bae Seongjae] Mm-hmm
[Bae Seongjae] Iya
[Yuha] and
[Yuha] Eh
[Yuha] use the four basic operations to quickly make 24, but it's kinda hard
[Yuha] pake operasi hitung dasar bisa cepet bikin angka 24, tapi ini agak susah
[Bae Seongjae] You look at those seven numbers on the license plate?
[Bae Seongjae] Liat tujuh angka di plat nomor mobil?
[Yuha] I look at four numbers
[Yuha] Empat angka
[Bae Seongjae] The last four digits
[Bae Seongjae] Empat angka terakhir
[Yuha] I can quickly make 24 using the four basic operations.
[Yuha] pake operasi hitung dasar bisa cepet bikin angka 24.
[Stella] She's really good at it. But
[Stella] Beneran jago. Tapi
[Bae Seongjae] That's genius-level stuff, right? Uh, multiplying and subtracting to make 24
[Bae Seongjae] Itu cerita jenius apa sih? Eh kali kurang gitu bikin 24 eh
[Bae Seongjae] So like
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau gitu
[Bae Seongjae] if the number is 3-3-8-6
[Bae Seongjae] 3 3 8 6 nomornya kayak gini.
[Yuha] 3-3-8-6. Then 3 times 3 equals 9, 9 minus 6 equals 3, 8 times 3 equals
[Yuha] 3 3 8 6 ya. Kalau gitu 3 kali 3 sama dengan 9, 9 kurang 6 sama dengan 3. 8 kali 3 sama dengan
[Yuha] 24
[Yuha] 24
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, this is really unique.
[Bae Seongjae] Wah ini beneran unik.
[Stella] Right?
[Stella] Kan?
[Bae Seongjae] How do you... but why are you so obsessed with 24? Can you do other numbers too?
[Bae Seongjae] Gimana sih tapi kenapa terus obsesi sama 24? Angka lain bisa gak?
[Yuha] No, I can't.
[Yuha] Gak. Gabisa.
[Yuha] Just 24.
[Yuha] 24.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, making 24 is like a hobby.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah bikin 24 itu kayak hobi ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh. Uh, but that's really fascinating.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh. Eh tapi aneh banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, you're really fast. Then what about 7-8-9-2?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh beneran cepet. Kalau gitu 7 8 9 2
[Bae Seongjae] 7-8-9-2
[Bae Seongjae] 7 8 9 2
[Yuha] These numbers
[Yuha] Angka ini
[Bae Seongjae] I should show you the numbers. 7-8-9-2
[Bae Seongjae] Harus tunjukin angkanya ya. 7 8 9 2
[Yuha] 7-8-9-2, there are numbers that don't work.
[Yuha] 7 8 9 2, ini juga ada angka yang gabisa soalnya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, you can immediately calculate which ones don't work. This one doesn't work
[Bae Seongjae] Ah yang gabisa langsung ketahuan juga ya hitungannya. Ini gabisa
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, amazing. Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Oh aneh. Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, then do you have good memory too? [Yuha] Yes, yes. Uh, when fans come once,
[Bae Seongjae] Ya kalau gitu daya ingat juga bagus gak? [Yuha] Ya ya. Eh, fans yang dateng sekali
[Yuha] I remember almost all of them well
[Yuha] hampir semua bisa inget gitu
[Bae Seongjae] Their faces
[Bae Seongjae] Wajahnya
[Yuha] Yeah. I remember faces well
[Yuha] Ya. Wajah bisa inget dengan baik
[Bae Seongjae] All those fans
[Bae Seongjae] Fans sebanyak itu
[Yuha] Yeah. I think so.
[Yuha] Ya. Kayaknya gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] Oh,
[Yuha] Like with license plates too, once I see them I'm like 'I've seen that car before'
[Yuha] Agak kayak plat nomor mobil juga sekali liat, ah ini mobil yang pernah diliat. Gitu
[Bae Seongjae] You remember cars you've seen before? Wow, that kind of memory is like
[Bae Seongjae] Mobil yang pernah diliat ya, wah daya ingat kayak gini hampir
[Bae Seongjae] investigator level, right? Investigators, police officers, detectives - you should work in the military
[Bae Seongjae] penyidik kan? Penyidik polisi kayak gitu, detektif harus jadi ya. Tentara
[Bae Seongjae] MP work, I can see that.
[Bae Seongjae] Penjaga keamanan pasti paham banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, do you remember names quickly too then?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, nama juga langsung inget gitu ya?
[Yuha] Yes. If I can match it with a face, I remember well.
[Yuha] Iya. Kalau bisa cocokkan sama wajah, ingetannya bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, so once you match a face with a name like that, you usually remember
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, wajah sama nama kalau udah dicocokkan sekali gitu pasti inget
[Bae Seongjae] it. Wow, I see.
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Wah, gitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, speaking of TMI, you debuted on February 24th.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, TMI tapi kepikiran kalian debut 24 Februari kan.
[Bae Seongjae] So getting the 24th right isn't just a coincidence
[Bae Seongjae] Jadi yang tadi nyebut tanggal 24 bukan karena itu kan
[Stella] That's right. Right. Correct. Correct.
[Stella] Bener. Bener kan. Bener. Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. You remember my name, right? Seongjae.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Nama saya inget kan? Seongjae.
[Bae Seongjae] Bae Seongjae, yes. Please memorize it once. When you come back in a few years,
[Bae Seongjae] Bae Seongjae iya. Hafalin ya. Nanti beberapa tahun lagi kalau datang lagi
[Bae Seongjae] I'll test you on it. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] bakal saya tes. Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, some people have called me Seo Seongjae, An Seongjae, and someone said the Seongjae type is the worst.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, ada yang bilang Seo Seongjae, ada yang bilang An Seongjae, ada yang bilang keluarga Seongjae paling parah.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, and I see you're good at Chinese.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, ternyata bahasa Cinanya bagus ya.
[Yuha] Ah, that's right. Uh,
[Yuha] Ah, bener. Eh,
[Bae Seongjae] What's your skill level? Are you native? [Yuha] No, not that level, just kinda
[Bae Seongjae] Sejauh mana kemampuannya? Native? [Yuha] Enggak. Segitunya sih enggak, cuma agak
[Yuha] I like watching Chinese dramas and stuff, so I learned a bit during trainee days too, so I can do just a little bit.
[Yuha] suka nonton drama Cina gitu jadi waktu trainee juga sempet belajar dikit jadi bisa dikit banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Which drama did you watch a lot?
[Bae Seongjae] Drama apa yang paling banyak ditonton?
[Yuha] My favorite one is a drama called 'Tutuzhangfuzhu'.
[Yuha] Yang paling suka tuh drama namanya Tutuzhangfuzhu.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, then how about greeting once in Chinese
[Bae Seongjae] Eh kalau gitu coba sapa pake bahasa Cina
[Yuha] Ah
[Yuha] Ah
[Bae Seongjae] Or try some drama lines? Or
[Bae Seongjae] Dialog drama coba? Atau
[Yuha] Hmm
[Yuha] Mm
[Yuha] Drama lines?
[Yuha] Dialog drama?
[Yuha] Yes. How about
[Yuha] Iya. Gimana
[Bae Seongjae] Any part from that drama, a dramatic part would be even better.
[Bae Seongjae] Itu drama bagian manapun yang dramatis lebih bagus lagi.
[Yuha] Let's go.
[Yuha] Ayo.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya.
[Yuha] Uh. Uh. Long se
[Yuha] Eh. Eh. 冷死了
[Bae Seongjae] What does that mean? "I'm hungry"? [Yuha] "I'm freezing to death."
[Bae Seongjae] Apa itu? Laper. [Yuha] Dingin banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Why did I think 'I'm hungry'? Aha, I see. Then how about
[Bae Seongjae] Kenapa saya pikir laper ya? Aha gitu ya. Kalau gitu gimana
[Bae Seongjae] greeting us in Chinese
[Bae Seongjae] pake bahasa Cina kita
[Bae Seongjae] once
[Bae Seongjae] sapa sekali
[Yuha] Uh,
[Yuha] Eh 大家好
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, somehow it sounds nice even just listening. What does it mean?
[Bae Seongjae] Ah rasanya enak aja didenger. Artinya apa?
[Yuha] Please listen to our new song RUDE a lot.
[Yuha] Lagu baru kami RUDE banyak-banyak didengerin ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, thank you. Really? Uh, you're really good at it. And
[Bae Seongjae] Ah terima kasih. Gitu ya? Eh beneran jago. Terus
[Bae Seongjae] is there anything else you're uniquely good at?
[Bae Seongjae] ada lagi yang jago secara unik
[Bae Seongjae] Going down stairs quickly? What's this? Going down stairs fast? Jumping down
[Bae Seongjae] turun tangga cepet? Ini apaan? Turun tangga cepet? Sekali lompat
[Bae Seongjae] in one go? Or going tap-tap-tap? [Yuha] I'm good at both.
[Bae Seongjae] jump gitu? Atau tap tap tap gitu? [Yuha] Dua-duanya jago.
[Yuha] I can jump down two steps at a time
[Yuha] Dua anak tangga sekaligus bisa loncat turun
[Yuha] or like teleportation, just like this
[Yuha] kayak pake ilmu meringankan tubuh gitu
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, like teleportation going tap-tap-tap too.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, kayak ilmu meringankan tubuh tap tap tap juga.
[Yuha] Yes.
[Yuha] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] But if there were, say, ten-step stairs,
[Bae Seongjae] Tapi kalau misalnya ada tangga sepuluh anak tangga.
[Yuha] Then I'd skip about five steps at a time.
[Yuha] Ya lima anak tangga sekaligus loncat turun.
[Bae Seongjae] Five steps at a time. Ah, you divide it in half, that's calculated too.
[Bae Seongjae] Lima anak tangga sekaligus. Ah, dibagi dua pas gitu ya, itu juga ada perhitungannya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, someone said to be careful with your joints
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, ada yang bilang hati-hati persendian
[Bae Seongjae] You gotta be careful with your joints. Yeah. And then, have any members
[Bae Seongjae] Harus hati-hati persendian ya. Iya. Terus kalau turun tangga cepat, apa member-member pernah
[Bae Seongjae] witnessed you going down stairs fast?
[Bae Seongjae] lihat?
[Stella] Oh. Ah when we were trainees preparing for debut, we said let's all exercise together, so we did stair
[Stella] Oh. Ah, waktu kami persiapan debut sebagai trainee, kita bilang ayo olahraga bareng, jadi naik turun
[Stella] climbing up and down, and Yuha was always super fast at it.
[Stella] tangga, tapi Yuha selalu ngeLakuin itu super cepet.
[Yuha] Yeah. I think I got good at it through that. Going down stairs quickly. Yeah.
[Yuha] Iya. Kayaknya dari situ aku belajar deh. Turun tangga dengan cepat. Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] But stairs, that's about having a feel for it too, right? You gotta match that step rhythm
[Bae Seongjae] Turun tangga itu juga butuh feeling kan? Gitu kan? Harus nyesuaiin langkah gitu
[Yuha] Yeah. Yeah. And you can't just squeeze your way down the stairs, you gotta
[Yuha] Iya. Iya. Terus agak kalau tangga gini gak boleh cuma turun biasa, tapi agak
[Yuha] bend your legs diagonally and place your feet like this
[Yuha] kaki harus ditekuk diagonal terus kakinya gini
[Yuha] Pro tip
[Yuha] Tips jitu
[Bae Seongjae] Then we should make this an ISAC event, right? Stairway to Heaven
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau gitu harus bikin cabang lomba untuk Idol Star Athletics Championships dong? Kan? Tangga surga
[Bae Seongjae] event where you go down fast and up fast. You walk like a sage.
[Bae Seongjae] bikin cabang lombanya, eh cepet turun cepet naik gitu harus dilakuin. Jalan kayak pertapa gitu ya
[Bae Seongjae] Someone said that. Yeah. Ah, and also anything else you're good at that you can
[Bae Seongjae] kata ada yang bilang gitu ya. Ah, terus juga kalau ada yang jago bisa nih
[Bae Seongjae] show off.
[Bae Seongjae] dipamerkan.
[Yuha] Show off.
[Yuha] Dipamerkan.
[Yuha] Yeah.
[Yuha] Mm.
[Yuha] What else is there? Hmm. Things I'm good at.
[Yuha] Apalagi ya? Mm. Yang jago.. yang jago.
[Yuha] Hmm.
[Yuha] Mm..
[Yuha] That's about it.
[Yuha] Segitu aja sih.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, listener doyukseongje said Yuha is good at four-character idiom quizzes, so I'd like to try that.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, Doyugseongje bilang Yuha jago kuis peribahasa empat karakter, coba dong.
[Bae Seongjae] Are you good with four-character idioms?
[Bae Seongjae] Jago peribahasa empat karakter?
[Yuha] Oh, let me try. [Bae Seongjae] Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay, so four-character idioms.
[Yuha] Oh, coba deh. [Bae Seongjae] Iya. Iya. Iya. Oke, peribahasa empat karakter.
[Yuha] Hmm.
[Yuha] Mm.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh. Gojin
[Bae Seongjae] Uh. Gojin
[Yuha] Gamrae
[Yuha] Gamlae
[Bae Seongjae] Gyeol-ja
[Bae Seongjae] Gyeolja
[Yuha] Haeji
[Yuha] Haeji
[Bae Seongjae] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Gwayu
[Bae Seongjae] Gwayu
[Yuha] Bulgup
[Yuha] Bulgeup
[Bae Seongjae] Seolsang
[Bae Seongjae] Seolsang
[Yuha] Gasang
[Yuha] Gasang
[Bae Seongjae] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Ipchun
[Bae Seongjae] Ipchun
[Yuha] Ipchun?
[Yuha] Ipchun?
[Yuha] Chosang (Give me a hint for the initials)
[Yuha] Inisial? (kasih hint inisial dong)
[Bae Seongjae] Uh demanding it right away, confidently. Yeah. D-sound memory
[Bae Seongjae] Eh langsung minta gitu? PD banget? ㄷ ㄱ
[Yuha] D-sound memory? [Stella] Look at the comments [Yuha] Daegil?
[Yuha] Digwit giyeok? [Stella] Liat komentar deh [Yuha] Daegil?
[Bae Seongjae] Hmm. Ah, Ipchun Daegil. Ah, this is kind of old culture so you might not
[Bae Seongjae] Mm. Ah, ipchun daegil. Ah, ini kan budaya lama jadi mungkin gak tau
[Bae Seongjae] know it. In the old days, like during the Joseon period or even recently at
[Bae Seongjae] kali ya. Dulu jaman Joseon atau bahkan sekarang juga di hanok gitu
[Bae Seongjae] traditional houses, they'd put up 'Ipchun Daegil' on the gate in spring.
[Bae Seongjae] ditempel di pintu gerbang, ipchun daegil waktu musim semi gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, then Hamheung
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, kalau gitu Hamheung
[Yuha] Chasa.
[Yuha] Chasa.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] Oh,
[Stella] Wow.
[Stella] Wow.
[Bae Seongjae] I was thinking naengmyeon earlier.
[Bae Seongjae] Aku tadi mikir naengmyeon.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, then Stella, give it a try.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, kalau gitu Stella coba.
[Stella] Ah, I
[Stella] Ah, aku
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Uh, four-character quiz. You can say anything for this. As long as it makes sense.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Eh kuis empat kata. Ini asal jawab aja boleh. Yang penting nyambung.
[Stella] Ah, got it.
[Stella] Ah oke.
[Bae Seongjae] Chadol
[Bae Seongjae] Chadol
[Stella] Baegi.
[Stella] Baegi.
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Easy, right? Comfortable, right? Uh, shoulder.
[Bae Seongjae] Gampang kan? Santai kan? Eh bahu.
[Stella] What?
[Stella] Hah?
[Bae Seongjae] Shoulder.
[Bae Seongjae] Bahu.
[Stella] Shoulder.
[Stella] Bahu.
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya.
[Stella] Say it quick.
[Stella] Cepetan dong.
[Yuha] Friend.
[Yuha] Teman.
[Stella] Friend.
[Stella] Teman.
[Stella] Right.
[Stella] Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Bank.
[Bae Seongjae] Bank.
[Stella] Bank? Deposit!
[Stella] Bank? Transfer!
[Bae Seongjae] That works. That works. Right. That's what matters most, right? Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Nyambung. Nyambung. Oke. Ini yang paling penting kan? Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, impossible?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh bulga?
[Stella] Impossible relationship.
[Stella] Bulgasari.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, good.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh bagus.
[Stella] Uh, I think I did well just now. [Bae Seongjae] Waist?
[Stella] Eh kayaknya bagus tuh. Barusan. [Bae Seongjae] Pinggang?
[Stella] Waist band
[Stella] Pinggang ikat
[Bae Seongjae] Waist band
[Bae Seongjae] Pinggang ikat
[Bae Seongjae] What we were expecting was hurricane but
[Bae Seongjae] Yang kita harapkan tuh hurricane tapi
[Bae Seongjae] if you pronounce it well, hurricane
[Bae Seongjae] Pronounnya kurang bagus hurricane
[Bae Seongjae] O-cane
[Bae Seongjae] Okane
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, fortune
[Bae Seongjae] Eh saju
[Stella] Fortune telling
[Stella] Ramalan nasib
[Bae Seongjae] Fortune telling
[Bae Seongjae] Ramalan nasib
[Stella] This is right, right? But doing it is right, right?
[Stella] Ini bener kan? Tapi jawabnya bener kan?
[Bae Seongjae] Right. Yes, that's right. I was thinking of fortune and destiny too. Earlier with bank,
[Bae Seongjae] Bener. Ya, bener. Saju palja juga kepikiran. Tadi bank itu
[Bae Seongjae] I was thinking of ginkgo tree. Then, bari
[Bae Seongjae] pohon ginkgo yang kepikiran. Kalau gitu bari
[Stella] Bari?
[Stella] Bari?
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Bari
[Bae Seongjae] Bari
[Stella] Barista.
[Stella] Barista.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh. This
[Bae Seongjae] Eh. I
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, Stella seems to pick up on the English words well.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, Stella kayaknya yang bahasa Inggris lebih kedengeran ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, good. Barista. Bulga.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, bagus. Barista. Bulga.
[Stella] Bulgasaui.
[Stella] Bulgasaui.
[Bae Seongjae] Bulgasaui. Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] Bulgasaui. Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] We wrote 'bulga' but 'bulgasaui' works too. Correct.
[Bae Seongjae] Kami nulis bulga tapi bulgasaui juga benar kok. Benar.
[Bae Seongjae] Bulgasari is a creature and bulgasaui is like, uh, something really mysterious in human history
[Bae Seongjae] Bulgasari itu makhluk hidup, bulgasaui itu hal yang sangat
[Bae Seongjae] Mystery, that kind of feeling. Mystery
[Bae Seongjae] misteri dalam sejarah manusia gitu. Misteri
[Bae Seongjae] Mystery-ari, if you listen casually
[Bae Seongjae] Misteri ari kalau dengerin sekilas
[Bae Seongjae] Uh
[Bae Seongjae] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Good. Yes. Now then, next
[Bae Seongjae] Bagus. Ya. Nah selanjutnya
[Bae Seongjae] Search term 'Gorgeous Snobby Girl'
[Bae Seongjae] Kata kunci 'Gorgeous Saechimddaegi'
[Bae Seongjae] I rolled my pronunciation without realizing it.
[Bae Seongjae] Gak sadar aku ngomongnya jadi aneh.
[Stella] Yes
[Stella] Ya
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, this is a nickname that member Ian made for Stella. How does it feel?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, ini panggilan yang dibuat Ian untuk Stella ya, gimana rasanya?
[Stella] Yes. Uh, when I speak English I kinda go 'gorgeous'
[Stella] Ya. Eh jadi pas aku ngomong bahasa Inggris agak gorgeous
[Stella] while being a bit snobby, so Ian said I'm like a gorgeous snobby girl.
[Stella] gitu terus agak jutek jadi Ian bilang aku kayak gorgeous saechimddaegi.
[Bae Seongjae] Gorgeous snobby girl.
[Bae Seongjae] Gorgeous saechimddaegi gitu.
[Stella] Yes. It's embarrassing.
[Stella] Ya. Malu.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, you have that cat-like look, right? Yes. But
[Bae Seongjae] Oh ini karena kamu agak cat-like ya? Ya. Tapi
[Bae Seongjae] rather than being snobby, you're actually full of aegyo.
[Bae Seongjae] sebenernya bukan saechimddaegi tapi aegyo queen ya.
[Stella] That's right.
[Stella] Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Right. Uh.
[Bae Seongjae] Kan. Oh.
[Bae Seongjae] Why? Why? Why? Have you ever fallen victim to her aegyo by any chance?
[Bae Seongjae] Kenapa? Kenapa? Kenapa? Pernah kena serangan aegyo gak?
[Yuha] Ah, but she's always like this. Lots of aegyo
[Yuha] Ah, tapi selalu kayak gini. Aegyo-nya banyak
[Yuha] Always like this.
[Yuha] selalu kayak gini.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, I just got that T vs F feeling. Someone said 'Stella kitty' is so
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, tadi berasa kayak T sama F gitu. Ada yang bilang 'Telnyangi' lucu
[Bae Seongjae] cute. Seohee said Stella's first impression was hot girl, personality was
[Bae Seongjae] banget. Seohee bilang kesan pertama Stella itu hot girl, kepribadiannya
[Bae Seongjae] cool girl, but how did you become full of aegyo now? What happened in between?
[Bae Seongjae] cool girl tapi sekarang kok jadi aegyo queen? Apa yang terjadi?
[Stella] But when I first joined SM, the members all said I had this really
[Stella] Tapi waktu pertama masuk SM, member-member bilang aku
[Stella] hot girl image. Back then I didn't really think of it that way, but
[Stella] banget image hot girl gitu. Waktu itu aku gak mikir kayak gitu sih
[Stella] thinking about it now, I was totally a hot girl.
[Stella] tapi sekarang dipikir-pikir kayaknya emang hot girl banget.
[Stella] Somehow I kinda became like this
[Stella] Gimana ya jadi kayak gini
[Bae Seongjae] Ah yes. Everyone's saying you're so pretty. How often do the members witness Stella's
[Bae Seongjae] Ah ya. Sekarang pada bilang cantik banget, gimana member-member sering liat
[Bae Seongjae] aegyo? Uh
[Bae Seongjae] aegyo Stella gak? Oh
[Yuha] Often, often. She keeps putting her hand on her chin
[Yuha] Sering, sering terus kayak gini tangan di dagu
[Yuha] and keeps making 'hmph' sounds like that
[Yuha] terus suaranya 'heung' kayak gitu
[Yuha] She does it often.
[Yuha] sering kayak gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, can you two reenact that situation? Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah bisa peragain situasinya gak? Ya.
[Stella] Uh yes
[Stella] Oh ya
[Stella] Mm
[Stella] Mm
[Stella] Oh yes, thank you.
[Stella] Oh ya terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, totally a T moment
[Bae Seongjae] Wah bener-bener T moment
[Bae Seongjae] Breathing in through the nose. Yes. Besides 'gorgeous snobby girl,' there's also
[Bae Seongjae] Napas lewat hidung. Ya. Selain gorgeous saechimddaegi ada panggilan
[Bae Seongjae] a nickname called 'Sstobbi.'
[Bae Seongjae] 'Sstobbi' juga ya.
[Bae Seongjae] What does this mean? [Stella] Haram made this one up
[Bae Seongjae] Ini artinya apa? [Stella] Ini Haram yang bikin jadi
[Yuha] It means 'Stella's sulking again'.
[Yuha] Artinya 'Stella lagi ngambek'.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, do you sulk a lot?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh sering ngambek?
[Yuha] She really sulks like ten times a day
[Yuha] Beneran sehari bisa sepuluh kali ngambek
[Stella] No I don't.
[Stella] Nggak kok.
[Bae Seongjae] Like when you act cute but the members don't respond, you might sulk a little. Yeah.
[Bae Seongjae] Mungkin pas lagi manja tapi member lain nggak respon, jadi agak ngambek gitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Is it like things where you think 'that's worth sulking over'?
[Bae Seongjae] Hal kayak gitu juga bisa jadi alasan ngambek?
[Yuha] Like someone ate the fruit she ordered for herself. Stuff like that.
[Yuha] Kayak buah yang dia pesen sendiri dimakan orang lain. Gitu.
[Stella] Ah but she shares it well though.
[Stella] Ah tapi dia makan dengan senang kok.
[Yuha] Right. It all works out in the end, but at first she definitely sulks no matter what.
[Yuha] Bener. Akhirnya sih baik-baik aja, tapi awalnya pasti ngambek dulu kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, sulk first. Well, if I ordered fruit and someone else ate it, that's worth getting upset over
[Bae Seongjae] Ah ngambek dulu ya. Eh buah yang aku pesen tapi dimakan orang lain, emang wajar kesel
[Bae Seongjae] isn't it?
[Bae Seongjae] kan?
[Yuha] Ah, isn't that worth sulking over?
[Yuha] Ah itu wajar ngambek kan?
[Stella] That's right. Thank you.
[Stella] Bener. Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Right. That's worth sulking over. [Stella] Ah really, so our members all just
[Bae Seongjae] Iya kan. Itu wajar ngambek. [Stella] Ah bener makanya member-member kita semua
[Stella] eat it too
[Stella] aku juga makan
[Stella] so I'm the only one who ends up sulking sometimes.
[Stella] jadi cuma aku sendiri yang suka ngambek kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] That's worth sulking over. Right? Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Itu wajar ngambek sih. Kan? Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone said 'Bae Seongjae Sstupit'
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang Bae Seongjae Sstopit
[Yuha] Ah, you really love food.
[Yuha] Ah ternyata suka banget sama makanan ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah right. Ah
[Bae Seongjae] Ah iya sih. Ah
[Bae Seongjae] When I said Sstupit, they told me to 'stop eat'.
[Bae Seongjae] Bilang Sstopit, terus ada yang bilang aku Stop-eat.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh I see. Haeeun Gongsa님 asked for a balance game. Forever in charge of aegyo
[Bae Seongjae] Oh gitu ya. Haeun-gongsa minta balance game. Selamanya jadi
[Bae Seongjae] vs forever in charge of charisma. Uh. Uh.
[Bae Seongjae] yang bertugas manja atau selamanya jadi yang bertugas karisma. Eh. Eh.
[Bae Seongjae] Aegyo vs charisma.
[Bae Seongjae] Manja vs karisma.
[Bae Seongjae] One, two, three.
[Bae Seongjae] Satu dua tiga.
[Stella] Charisma.
[Stella] Karisma.
[Yuha] Aegyo.
[Yuha] Manja.
[Stella] Oh.
[Stella] Oh.
[Yuha] Yes. What about you?
[Yuha] Ya. Eh kamu kenapa?
[Bae Seongjae] You didn't match.
[Bae Seongjae] Nggak sama.
[Stella] Ah I just
[Stella] Ah aku tuh
[Stella] kind of want to be cool.
[Stella] pengen jadi keren gitu.
[Stella] Hello.
[Stella] Annyeonghaseyo.
[Bae Seongjae] The expression you're making while saying that is overflowing with aegyo.
[Bae Seongjae] Ekspresi waktu ngomong gitu keliatan imut banget sih.
[Stella] Ah why is Haram aegyo? I think I'm charismatic.
[Stella] Ah Haram kenapa manja? Aku pikir karisma.
[Yuha] I don't have a charismatic personality, so having aegyo would be
[Yuha] Aku orangnya nggak ada karisma jadi kayaknya yang agak manja lebih
[Yuha] more comfortable, don't you think? [Bae Seongjae] Ah, I see.
[Yuha] nyaman nggak sih? [Bae Seongjae] Ah, gitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone said 'Canada cutie' and yes, someone said their preference is the opposite
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang si imut Kanada, terus ada yang bilang vibenya kebalikan
[Bae Seongjae] And Yuha, your nickname is 'first love girl'
[Bae Seongjae] Dan Yuha punya julukan si cinta pertama
[Yuha] Mm
[Yuha] Mm
[Bae Seongjae] Yes, first love visual. Do you personally
[Bae Seongjae] Ya visual cinta pertama, kamu sendiri gimana
[Bae Seongjae] acknowledge that part too?
[Bae Seongjae] ngakuin nggak?
[Yuha] Uh, do I acknowledge it? Uh, acknowledging
[Yuha] Eh aku ngakuin? Eh ngakuin
[Stella] I acknowledge it. Right?
[Stella] Ngakuin. Kan?
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, kind of right? Like a female lead vibe. Someone said 'Architecture Yuha' and yes
[Bae Seongjae] Eh kayak gitu kan? Tipe pemeran utama gitu. Ada yang bilang Yuha Arsitektur, terus ya
[Bae Seongjae] someone said 'where can you find such a pretty first love girl'
[Bae Seongjae] ada yang bilang dimana sih cinta pertama secantik itu
[Bae Seongjae] Oh Yuha, do you have any nickname
[Bae Seongjae] Eh Yuha kamu kayak 'Sstobbi' ada julukan
[Bae Seongjae] worth sharing like 'Sstobbi'?
[Bae Seongjae] yang bisa dibagi gak?
[Yuha] For nicknames, I have a nickname called Hamong that my dad gave me
[Yuha] Julukan aku ada julukan Hamong yang dikasih sama ayahku
[Bae Seongjae] Hamong, isn't that the delicious thing?
[Bae Seongjae] Hamong itu ham yang enak itu bukan?
[Yuha] Woof woof
[Yuha] Guk guk
[Yuha] Mm
[Yuha] Um
[Bae Seongjae] Hamong
[Bae Seongjae] Hamong
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah
[Bae Seongjae] Ya
[Yuha] Dad gave it to me, kinda meaning I'm dumb
[Yuha] Ayah yang kasih tapi agak bodoh gitu
[Stella] Really?
[Stella] Beneran?
[Stella] That's not true, really?
[Stella] Engga kan beneran?
[Bae Seongjae] It's not like spacing out, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Meong meong kena bukan
[Yuha] That meaning too, and I space out a lot
[Yuha] Ada arti itu juga dan sering kena memar juga
[Yuha] and make some dumb comments to dad
[Yuha] agak ngomong bodoh ke ayah
[Bae Seongjae] No way, to a genius daughter who speaks 3 languages and finds 24 like that, does
[Bae Seongjae] Lah bisa 3 bahasa dan bisa nemuin 24 kayak gitu anak jenius tapi
[Bae Seongjae] your father perhaps have like three PhD degrees?
[Bae Seongjae] ayahnya jangan-jangan punya gelar doktor sekitar 3 gitu?
[Yuha] No. My dad
[Yuha] Engga. Ayahku
[Bae Seongjae] Mm
[Bae Seongjae] Iya
[Yuha] In front of dad, kinda
[Yuha] Di depan ayah agak
[Yuha] I don't know. How I was [Bae Seongjae] Like a baby always in front of dad, so dad also
[Yuha] gatau deh. Gimana ya [Bae Seongjae] kayak anak kecil selalu di depan ayah jadi eh ayah juga
[Bae Seongjae] Is he perhaps a T type?
[Bae Seongjae] jangan-jangan T ya?
[Yuha] Yeah ISTJ
[Yuha] Iya ISTJ
[Bae Seongjae] Wow swept competition awards right? Yeah. Plays piano so well, good memory
[Bae Seongjae] Wah kompetisi musik juara semua kan? Ya. Piano juga jago banget main dan daya ingatnya juga
[Bae Seongjae] and all that. Yeah. Got it.
[Bae Seongjae] bagus banget gitu. Ya. Oke paham.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, next search term. Menu obsession.
[Bae Seongjae] Oke, kata kunci selanjutnya. Menu gofik.
[Yuha] Mm.
[Yuha] Um.
[Bae Seongjae] This is Yuha's keyword. They say when you get hooked on one food, you only eat that until you're sick of it.
[Bae Seongjae] Kata kunci Yuha nih. Kalau udah suka satu makanan sampai bosen cuma makan itu terus katanya.
[Yuha] That's right.
[Yuha] Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. What food are you hooked on recently?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. Makanan apa yang lagi disukai belakangan ini?
[Yuha] Right now, just this week I got hooked on honey rice cake.
[Yuha] Sekarang pas minggu ini lagi suka banget kkul-seolgi
[Bae Seongjae] What's honey rice cake?
[Bae Seongjae] Kkul-seolgi itu apa?
[Yuha] It's white rice cake with honey inside.
[Yuha] Baekseolgi yang ada madunya di dalamnya
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, do they sell that separately these days? Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, ada yang jual kayak gitu sekarang ya? Wah,
[Yuha] I've been eating that every single day for a whole week.
[Yuha] Itu aku makan seminggu penuh setiap hari.
[Bae Seongjae] But if you eat stuff like that, meals might not be appealing, is that separate?
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau makan gituan tapi makan nasi jadi agak gak nafsu mungkin ya itu terpisah?
[Yuha] I kinda have meals through snacking
[Yuha] Aku orangnya agak makan cemilan jadi makan sih
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, so you're using honey rice cake like meals these days
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, kkul-seolgi malah sekarang dijadiin kayak makan juga
[Yuha] Yeah, that's right.
[Yuha] Ya, bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, I'll look into honey rice cake. I should try it too. So what other
[Bae Seongjae] Wah, kkul-seolgi mau aku cari tau. Aku juga mau coba sekali. Terus belakangan ini
[Bae Seongjae] foods have you been hooked on recently?
[Bae Seongjae] makanan yang disukai lainnya apa lagi?
[Yuha] Before honey rice cake, it was mocha bread
[Yuha] Sebelum kkul-seolgi itu roti mocha
[Yuha] It was mocha bread, and before that
[Yuha] roti mocha dan sebelumnya
[Yuha] what, yogurt
[Yuha] apa ya yakult
[Bae Seongjae] Mm,
[Bae Seongjae] Um,
[Yuha] Banana Kick. Seaweed soup sujebi, stuff like that
[Yuha] Banana Kick. Sup rumput laut sujebi gitu-gitu
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, your tastes are distinct but also kinda, you know? Yeah.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah selera kamu tegas tapi gimana ya? Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] It doesn't feel like there's a clear pattern - you're really the type who eats something when you're totally hooked on it.
[Bae Seongjae] Kayaknya bukan yang ada alurnya gitu, tapi beneran tipe yang kalau udah suka langsung makan terus ya.
[Yuha] Yeah. Just that one thing for months
[Yuha] Ya. Sampai berbulan-bulan cuma itu doang
[Bae Seongjae] Someone said you have grandma taste buds.
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang selera kamu kayak nenek-nenek.
[Bae Seongjae] Easy to chew stuff. Yeah. Yogurt and
[Bae Seongjae] Yang gampang dikunyah gitu. Ya. Yogurt sama
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. And banana snacks. Mm. I see.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Sama banana kick. Hmm. Begitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh. Do you also remember good restaurants like that? Like
[Bae Seongjae] Eh. Kalau gitu kamu juga suka nyimpen restoran favorit gitu? Kayak
[Bae Seongjae] 'I went to this place recently and I really need to come here often.'
[Bae Seongjae] Belakangan ini coba ke tempat ini, wah tempat ini harus sering-sering datang nih.
[Yuha] Yeah. Yeah. With restaurants too, when I get hooked on one, I just keep going there for a really long time
[Yuha] Ya. Ya. Kalau udah suka sama restorannya ya cuma ke situ doang terus, sering banget ke sana
[Bae Seongjae] What kind of restaurant do you like best?
[Bae Seongjae] Restoran apa yang paling kamu suka?
[Yuha] What I'm obsessed with lately is seaweed soup sujebi.
[Yuha] Yang lagi aku suka sekarang tuh sup rumput laut sujebi.
[Bae Seongjae] Seaweed soup sujebi. Oh I see. What's the best way to eat that? Do you need to have it with kimchi or something?
[Bae Seongjae] Sup rumput laut sujebi. Oh begitu ya. Cara makan yang enak gimana? Harus dimakan bareng kimchi gitu?
[Yuha] They sell seaweed soup sujebi and water parsley pancake together.
[Yuha] Sup rumput laut sujebi sama jeon daun selasih dijual bareng.
[Yuha] Yeah. When you eat them together, it's really delicious.
[Yuha] Ya. Kalau makan bareng itu beneran enak banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Before you leave later, write down where that is for me. I'll go check it out too.
[Bae Seongjae] Nanti sebelum pulang tulis dong tempatnya dimana. Aku juga mau coba ke sana.
[Bae Seongjae] See, people are saying your taste is exactly like our grandma's. Water parsley, right. Yeah. But like
[Bae Seongjae] Lihat tuh, selera kamu sama persis kayak nenek aku. Daun selasih ya. Ya. Tapi kayaknya
[Bae Seongjae] Do you prefer vegetables? More than meat? Or not really?
[Bae Seongjae] Kamu suka vegetarian? Daripada daging? Bukan gitu?
[Yuha] No. I'm actually a really picky eater
[Yuha] Bukan. Aku tuh pilih-pilih banget makannya
[Yuha] I can only eat water parsley pancakes.
[Yuha] Cuma jeon daun selasih doang yang bisa aku makan.
[Bae Seongjae] And Stella, you're a dessert lover
[Bae Seongjae] Terus Stella kamu dessert lover
[Bae Seongjae] I see. What kind of desserts do you love so much? [Stella] I like everything
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Dessert apa yang kamu suka banget? [Stella] Aku sih semua suka sih
[Stella] but I really love tiramisu cake and cheesecake.
[Stella] tapi aku beneran suka banget tiramisu cake sama cheesecake.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, cake types
[Bae Seongjae] Ah yang jenis cake
[Stella] I really love cake
[Stella] Aku beneran suka banget cake
[Stella] I love chocolate so much that I eat chocolate every single day
[Stella] Suka banget cokelat jadi setiap hari makan cokelat
[Bae Seongjae] You eat it every day?
[Bae Seongjae] Setiap hari makan?
[Stella] Yeah, almost every day
[Stella] Ya hampir setiap hari
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, so for stuff like tiramisu, do you actually go buy it or order delivery
[Bae Seongjae] Oh kalau gitu tiramisu gitu gimana caranya, beli ke toko atau pesan delivery
[Stella] I always order delivery
[Stella] Pesan delivery, selalu gitu
[Bae Seongjae] Do you share it? Or are you the type to eat it alone?
[Bae Seongjae] Dibagi-bagi gitu? Atau dimakan sendiri?
[Yuha] She eats it all herself, and whatever's left over
[Yuha] Dia habiskan sendiri semua, yang sisa baru dia
[Bae Seongjae] You eat as much as you want and then what's left, how do you want to eat it? [Yuha] She has a really small appetite.
[Bae Seongjae] Makan sepuasnya terus sisanya gimana mau dimakan? [Yuha] Soalnya dia makannya sedikit banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, she also has a small appetite.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, makannya juga sedikit.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, and someone said she's sulking again.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, ada yang bilang ngambek lagi.
[Yuha] If you do this, she'll be sulking when it's over.
[Yuha] Kalau gini nanti habis ini pasti ngambek.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, I see. But you're actually in your promotion period right now, and I heard earlier that you had chicken and pizza too.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, begitu ya. Tapi sekarang kan lagi periode aktivitas, tadi dengar-dengar makan ayam juga, pizza juga.
[Yuha] Yeah. We also had cheesecake today.
[Yuha] Ya. Hari ini juga makan cheesecake lagi.
[Bae Seongjae] Cheesecake too - you still eat well while promoting. Still.
[Bae Seongjae] Cheesecake juga tetap makan sambil aktivitas ya. Bagus.
[Yuha] Yeah. We really love eating and we eat well. Yeah. [Bae Seongjae] Then actually
[Yuha] Ya. Kami suka banget makan dan makan dengan baik. Ya. [Bae Seongjae] Kalau begitu malah
[Bae Seongjae] during practice period, before promotion period starts, do you manage yourselves more?
[Bae Seongjae] Periode latihan, sebelum masuk periode aktivitas malah agak dijaga gitu?
[Yuha] It's always pretty similar, but our thing is let's eat delicious food in moderation.
[Yuha] Selalu mirip-mirip sih, kami makannya yang enak tapi secukupnya aja.
[Stella] That's right. That's right.
[Stella] Bener. Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, so you don't eat until you're stuffed, but you freely choose what you want to eat.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, jadi bukan yang makan sampai kekenyangan gitu, tapi menunya bebas aja gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, that's nice.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Do you two have compatible food tastes? How is it?
[Bae Seongjae] Kalian berdua cocok gak sih selera makannya? Gimana?
[Yuha] I think we match well. We both like sweet foods.
[Yuha] Cocok kayaknya. Suka makanan manis.
[Bae Seongjae] Sweet stuff. Oh, then let me check if you really match or not.
[Bae Seongjae] Yang manis-manis ya. Oh, kalau gitu coba kita cek dulu cocok atau engga.
[Bae Seongjae] This isn't in the script, members.
[Bae Seongjae] Member-member, ini gak ada di script ya.
[Stella] Ah, okay.
[Stella] Ah, iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Mint choco lovers vs anti-mint choco. One, two, three.
[Bae Seongjae] Mint choco vs anti-mint choco. Satu, dua, tiga.
[Stella] Anti-mint choco
[Stella] Anti-mint choco
[Bae Seongjae] You don't match at all. Right from the start. What about bungeoppang? Red bean vs cream
[Bae Seongjae] Sama sekali gak cocok nih. Dari awal udah. Bungeoppang. Kacang merah vs krim
[Stella] Cream! This one we have to fight over.
[Stella] Kacang merah! Ini harus berantem nih.
[Bae Seongjae] No need to even do one, two, three. Why why why are you like this again?
[Bae Seongjae] Gak perlu satu dua tiga juga. Kenapa kenapa kenapa kayak gini lagi
[Stella] I'm completely red bean and Haram is completely cream, so
[Stella] Aku tuh banget kacang merah, terus Haram tuh banget krim
[Stella] I can't understand it.
[Stella] Aku gak ngerti.
[Yuha] I don't eat red bean bungeoppang at all either
[Yuha] Aku juga kacang merah sama sekali gak makan soalnya
[Bae Seongjae] Not at all? [Stella] Not at all.
[Bae Seongjae] Sama sekali gak makan? [Stella] Sama sekali gak makan.
[Bae Seongjae] That's not easy, I mean
[Bae Seongjae] Itu gak gampang loh, jadi gimana
[Bae Seongjae] Well, bungeoppang usually goes like 1st choice, 2nd choice - you don't completely reject the other side.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh bungeoppang kan biasanya ada prioritas 1, prioritas 2 gitu, gak sampai menolak yang lain kan.
[Stella] I don't eat cream bungeoppang at all either. I've never even tried it.
[Stella] Aku juga krim sama sekali gak makan. Belum pernah coba.
[Bae Seongjae] Never tried it? Haven't even put it to your lips?
[Bae Seongjae] Belum pernah coba, belum pernah nyentuh mulut sama sekali?
[Stella] No.
[Stella] Iya.
[Stella] I don't want to eat it.
[Stella] Gak mau makan.
[Bae Seongjae] If you try it once, your mind might change.
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau sekali dicoba bisa aja berubah pikiran loh.
[Stella] Ah it's fine. No, it's fine.
[Stella] Ah gak papa. Eh gak papa.
[Bae Seongjae] What about red bean then
[Bae Seongjae] Kacang merah gimana
[Bae Seongjae] Red bean? [Yuha] Uh, not at all
[Bae Seongjae] Kacang merah? [Yuha] Eh sama sekali
[Bae Seongjae] Oh I see. For mint choco vs anti-mint choco, who was the mint choco lover?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh begitu. Mint choco sama anti-mint choco tadi siapa yang mint choco?
[Yuha] Me, mint choco [Stella] I really hate it.
[Yuha] Aku mint choco [Stella] Aku beneran benci banget.
[Stella] The worst. The worst of the worst
[Stella] Terburuk. Terburuk dari yang terburuk
[Bae Seongjae] Oh I see. In a way, having compatible food tastes means you don't encroach on each other's
[Bae Seongjae] Oh begitu. Kalau dipikir-pikir selera makan yang cocok itu karena gak saling ganggu
[Bae Seongjae] territory, so that's why you match?
[Bae Seongjae] makanya cocok gitu?
[Yuha] Yeah. I guess that's how it works.
[Yuha] Iya. Sepertinya begitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Then tteokbokki vs chicken. One two three
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau gitu tteokbokki vs ayam. Satu dua tiga
[Stella] Chicken. [Yuha] Chicken.
[Stella] Ayam. [Yuha] Ayam.
[Stella] This is it
[Stella] Ini nih
[Bae Seongjae] It's not that you hate tteokbokki? [Yuha] I just love chicken too much.
[Bae Seongjae] Tteokbokki bukan yang dibenci kan? [Yuha] Ayam terlalu suka.
[Bae Seongjae] What kind of chicken? Fried or seasoned?
[Bae Seongjae] Ayam yang mana? Fried chicken? Atau yang bumbu?
[Stella] Lately I like fried - I used to like seasoned but lately fried
[Stella] Sekarang aku fried chicken, dulu bumbu tapi sekarang fried chicken
[Bae Seongjae] You used to but oh
[Bae Seongjae] Dulu tapi eh
[Yuha] I like seasoned these days
[Yuha] Aku sekarang bumbu
[Bae Seongjae] Seasoned
[Bae Seongjae] Bumbu
[Bae Seongjae] Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Eh
[Stella] So now we just order half and half and share peacefully [Bae Seongjae] Oh the food distribution works out well somehow.
[Stella] Jadi sekarang pesen setengah-setengah terus makan bareng dengan damai [Bae Seongjae] Eh makanan bagi-baginya bagus banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Do you have a favorite brand? [Yuha] Can I mention the brand?
[Bae Seongjae] Ada brand favorit gak? [Yuha] Brand boleh sebut gak?
[Bae Seongjae] Chicken brand. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Brand ayam. Iya.
[Yuha] I like Cheogajip Supreme seasoned chicken.
[Yuha] Aku Cheogajip Supreme bumbu.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah. Ah.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah. Ah.
[Bae Seongjae] That's really delicious. Yeah. Good choice. Good choice. And
[Bae Seongjae] Itu emang enak banget sih. Eh. Bagus. Bagus. Terus
[Stella] I like BBQ Fried Golden these days
[Stella] Aku sekarang suka BBQ Fried Golden
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, so detailed and good.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah detail dan bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah nice. You both choose well. You're both food connoisseurs.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah bagus. Kalian pilih dengan baik. Kalian berdua jago milih makanan ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone in the chat says 'Yuha has the same taste as my grandma'.
[Bae Seongjae] Di chat ada yang bilang Yuha selera makannya kayak nenek aku.
[Bae Seongjae] Alright, sweet potato vs. potato. One, two, three
[Bae Seongjae] Nah kalau gitu ubi vs kentang. Satu dua tiga
[Stella] Sweet potato - we
[Stella] Ubi, ini kita
[Stella] match well on this
[Stella] cocok
[Bae Seongjae] This is something I kind of knew about. It's not that you hate potatoes?
[Bae Seongjae] Sebagian udah tau sih. Bukan berarti kamu ga suka kentang kan?
[Stella] I like potatoes.
[Stella] Aku suka kentang.
[Yuha] I just love sweet potatoes too much
[Yuha] Terlalu suka ubi
[Stella] I love sweet potatoes
[Stella] Karena cinta sama ubi
[Bae Seongjae] Then triangle kimbap. Lastly
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau gitu onigiri. Yang terakhir
[Bae Seongjae] Jeonju bibim vs. tuna mayo. One, two, three
[Bae Seongjae] Jeonju bibim vs tuna mayo. Satu dua tiga
[Stella] Jeonju bibim [Yuha] Tuna mayo
[Stella] Jeonju bibim [Yuha] Tuna mayo
[Bae Seongjae] Aha I see. Got it. We looked at triangle kimbap too and
[Bae Seongjae] Aha begitu ya. Oke. Sampe onigiri juga udah kita bahas tapi eh
[Bae Seongjae] looking at it, you two really seem to divide food preferences well.
[Bae Seongjae] Ternyata kalian berdua beneran beda-beda ya soal makanan.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, the next keyword is Han River cycling.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, keyword berikutnya adalah sepeda Hangang.
[Bae Seongjae] This is Stella's keyword.
[Bae Seongjae] Ini keyword Stella.
[Bae Seongjae] You're really good at riding bikes
[Bae Seongjae] Karena kamu jago banget naik sepeda
[Stella] That's right.
[Stella] Benar.
[Bae Seongjae] You have cycling pride.
[Bae Seongjae] Sampe bangga gitu sama sepedanya.
[Stella] Yes. That's right.
[Stella] Ya. Benar.
[Bae Seongjae] I saw that Stella told S2U 'If you see me cycling at Han River
[Bae Seongjae] Eh katanya Stella bilang ke S2U kalau aku naik sepeda di Hangang
[Bae Seongjae] you'll just fall for me'
[Bae Seongjae] langsung jatuh cinta
[Bae Seongjae] You wrote something like that
[Bae Seongjae] gitu juga ada
[Bae Seongjae] Too cool hehe.
[Bae Seongjae] Terlalu keren sih hahaha.
[Bae Seongjae] How well do you ride? [Stella] I just fly. When I ride a bike
[Bae Seongjae] Seberapa jago sih? [Stella] Aku ya terbang aja. Kalau naik sepeda
[Stella] I just go whoosh like this. I'm just so proud of myself. So
[Stella] Ya langsung whoosh gitu. Aku tuh bangga banget. Makanya
[Stella] Yeah.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Do you ride your own bike? Or do you rent like Ttareungyi?
[Bae Seongjae] Kamu naik sepeda sendiri? Atau sewa Ttareungyi gitu?
[Stella] Yeah. I rent
[Stella] Ya. Sewa
[Bae Seongjae] Ah you fly on Ttareungyi. But Ttareungyi only goes up to 40km at most.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah naik Ttareungyi terus terbang. Ttareungyi mah kencangnya paling cuma 40km doang.
[Stella] From what I felt, I was flying. That's how it felt.
[Stella] Yang aku rasain sih lagi terbang. Gitu rasanya.
[Bae Seongjae] You don't ride hands-free or anything. [Stella] I can do it with one hand.
[Bae Seongjae] Ga pake tangan gitu? [Stella] Satu tangan bisa kok.
[Bae Seongjae] Just one hand? [Stella] Cool, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Satu tangan doang? [Stella] Keren kan?
[Stella] Or not?
[Stella] Atau engga?
[Bae Seongjae] Aha, I see. So you don't have your own bike yet?
[Bae Seongjae] Aha, begitu ya. Berarti sepeda sendiri belum punya?
[Stella] Oh, I have one in Canada but since coming to Korea I can't ride often
[Stella] Eh, ada di Kanada sih tapi sejak di Korea jadi jarang
[Bae Seongjae] Is the bike in Canada like a really good bike? Or
[Bae Seongjae] Sepeda di Kanada itu sepeda bagus? Atau
[Stella] Oh, yeah. I think so.
[Stella] Eh, ya. Kayaknya gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] It's not like the one you rode as a kid, right?
[Bae Seongjae] Bukan yang dari kecil kan?
[Stella] That's right.
[Stella] Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] The one from when you were little, the one dad bought you. Oh
[Bae Seongjae] Yang dari kecil, yang dibeliin ayah. Eh
[Bae Seongjae] Usually in Korea when we talk about cycling pride, it means using expensive equipment
[Bae Seongjae] Biasanya di Korea kalau bangga sama sepeda itu pake sepeda mahal atau equipment mahal gitu
[Stella] Ah so it's not to that extent
[Stella] Ah jadi nggak sampai segitunya
[Bae Seongjae] Not to that extent, uh, do you ride with all the gear? Or just like that
[Bae Seongjae] Bukan sampai segitu dan eh itu gimana, pakai peralatan lengkap gitu? Atau cuma begini aja
[Bae Seongjae] People who ride bikes, those shoes that clip
[Bae Seongjae] Yang naik sepeda itu kan ada yang pakai sepatu khusus yang kakinya
[Stella] into the pedals and stuff like that
[Stella] dikaitkan gitu
[Bae Seongjae] You don't do that?
[Bae Seongjae] Nggak pakai yang begituan?
[Stella] First time hearing about it.
[Stella] Baru denger.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah I see. In the chat, someone said after listening, it sounds like just regular riding
[Bae Seongjae] Ah begitu. Di chat ternyata ada yang bilang kayaknya cuma naik sepeda biasa aja
[Bae Seongjae] so they don't know why there'd be any pride in it
[Bae Seongjae] jadi nggak ngerti kenapa bisa pamer
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, someone said they thought you meant unicycling.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh ada juga yang bilang kirain naik sepeda roda satu.
[Bae Seongjae] Why are you guys putting our Stella down? Just say it's amazing.
[Bae Seongjae] Stella kita jangan direndahin, bilang aja keren udah.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh but there's an eyewitness account. You rode by noisily near Ttukseom. What's the noisy part?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh tapi ada yang lihat. Di Ttukseom lewat naik sepeda sambil ribut-ribut. Ribut-ribut apanya?
[Stella] Uh, music. Ian and I rode together
[Stella] Eh itu lagu. Aku sama Ian naik bareng
[Stella] and we had the music turned up loud
[Stella] lagu dikerasin
[Stella] Ah we had music playing and singing along, singing along
[Stella] Ah lagu dikerasin terus sambil nyanyi sambil nyanyi
[Stella] Uh I remember riding enthusiastically
[Stella] eh semangat banget naik sepedanya
[Bae Seongjae] Uh that sounds so fun
[Bae Seongjae] Eh asik banget itu
[Bae Seongjae] I saw on SNS a few days ago, Dahyeon and Ian on a tandem bike at Ttukseom
[Bae Seongjae] Lihat di SNS beberapa hari lalu Dahyeon sama Ian naik sepeda tandem di Ttukseom
[Bae Seongjae] singing I Got a Boy while zooming by lololol
[Bae Seongjae] sambil nyanyi I Got a Boy lewat begitu aja wkwkwkwk
[Stella] Yeah
[Stella] Iya
[Bae Seongjae] Ah you rode a tandem?
[Bae Seongjae] Ah naik yang tandem?
[Stella] Yeah, I was in the front seat of the tandem and I think I was really good at it
[Stella] Iya aku duduk di depan sepeda tandem, menurutku aku tuh jago banget ah
[Stella] I think Ian acknowledged it too
[Stella] Ian juga kayaknya ngaku
[Bae Seongjae] Did she acknowledge it from behind? Like 'Stella rides so well'?
[Bae Seongjae] Ngaku dari belakang? Eh Stella jago banget.
[Stella] 'So good. So good at avoiding things' and stuff like that
[Stella] Jago banget. Jago banget nghindarnya begitu
Uh yeah
eh iya
[Bae Seongjae] Wasn't it hard?
[Bae Seongjae] Nggak capek?
[Stella] No.
[Stella] Nggak.
[Stella] It was totally easy.
[Stella] Gampang banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, I guess because your lower body is somewhat trained. Oh, nice.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, soalnya otot kaki udah terlatih. Oh, bagus.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, and also on SNS, someone said two incredibly loud girls on bikes
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, terus ada lagi di SNS dari arah seberang ada dua cewe ribut banget naik sepeda
[Bae Seongjae] were coming down the road and they wondered what it was, but when they could see clearly,
[Bae Seongjae] ke jalan raya, kirain apaan, eh pas deket bisa keliatan
[Bae Seongjae] Stella was in front and Ian in back.
[Bae Seongjae] depan Stella belakang Ian.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, they witnessed that rare sight. Someone's asking if you were going around for promotion,
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, langka banget bisa lihat gitu. Ini buat promosi ya katanya,
[Bae Seongjae] self-promotion. Did the company create viral marketing? [Stella] We kind of had that in mind.
[Bae Seongjae] promosi sendiri. Jangan-jangan ini viral marketing perusahaan? [Stella] Agak ada maksudnya sih.
[Bae Seongjae] Kind of? Front-Stella-Back-Ian.
[Bae Seongjae] Agak? Depan Stella belakang Ian.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, I see. So Dahyeon is Stella's Korean name.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, begitu. Jadi Dahyeon itu nama Korea Stella.
[Bae Seongjae] Dahyeon and Ian like this
[Bae Seongjae] Dahyeon sama Ian begini
[Bae Seongjae] They saw you both at once it seems. Hmm. So did you just
[Bae Seongjae] langsung keliatan kayaknya. Hmm. Terus ke Han River cuma naik sepeda
[Bae Seongjae] ride bikes at the Han River? Or did you have some ramen too?
[Bae Seongjae] aja? Atau makan ramyeon juga?
[Stella] Uh that time we just rode bikes.
[Stella] Eh waktu itu cuma naik sepeda aja.
[Bae Seongjae] Just bikes.
[Bae Seongjae] Cuma sepeda.
[Stella] Yeah. We originally planned to eat tteokbokki but riding bikes was so
[Stella] Iya. Waktu itu sebenernya mau makan tteokbokki tapi naik sepedanya terlalu
[Stella] fun that we just rode bikes for like three hours straight
[Stella] seru jadinya tiga jam terus naik sepeda aja
[Bae Seongjae] Three hours? Uh if it's that much, you can have some pride
[Bae Seongjae] Tiga jam? Eh kalau segitu pantas lah pamer
[Bae Seongjae] I see. The Han River is really great for biking.
[Bae Seongjae] Begitu. Han River emang enak buat naik sepeda.
[Stella] Right.
[Stella] Bener.
[Bae Seongjae] There's lots of Ttareungi bikes too.
[Bae Seongjae] Ttareungi-nya juga banyak.
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha, did you ever think about joining the biking?
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha, kamu nggak kepikiran ikut naik sepeda juga?
[Yuha] I don't think I'm good at biking.
[Yuha] Kayaknya aku nggak bisa naik sepeda.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, have you never tried? [Yuha] I have tried but
[Bae Seongjae] Ah belum pernah coba? [Yuha] Pernah sih coba
[Yuha] I'm not that good at it so it's a bit scary.
[Yuha] tapi nggak begitu bisa jadi agak takut.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, are you avoiding it on purpose? In case you get dragged out a few times.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, jangan-jangan sengaja menghindar? Takut diseret keluar berkali-kali.
[Bae Seongjae] In case you keep getting dragged out.
[Bae Seongjae] Takut terus diseret keluar.
[Yuha] No.
[Yuha] Bukan.
[Bae Seongjae] No?
[Bae Seongjae] Bukan?
[Bae Seongjae] You use teleportation, so bikes must feel frustrating. Yeah, I see.
[Bae Seongjae] Kamu kan bisa teleportasi, naik sepeda pasti terasa lambat ya. Iya, begitu ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow, three hours
[Bae Seongjae] Wah, tiga jam itu
[Stella] It really was three hours.
[Stella] Beneran tiga jam.
[Stella] Yeah.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. Three hours on a tandem bike would be really tough.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Sepeda tandem tiga jam itu beneran capek lho.
[Bae Seongjae] I acknowledge that. I acknowledge that. [Stella] Thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] Ini sih diakui. Diakui. [Stella] Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Okay, the next keyword is tyrant.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, kata kunci selanjutnya adalah tiran.
[Bae Seongjae] This is Yuha's keyword - tyrant.
[Bae Seongjae] Ini kata kunci Yuha, tiran.
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. So this was a major nickname you were hiding earlier.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Ini julukan utamanya ya, tadi disembunyiin ternyata ada ini.
[Bae Seongjae] You have this innocent image and that crystal-like voice, but tyrant moments sometimes
[Bae Seongjae] Padahal image-nya polos dan suaranya kayak kelereng kaca gitu tapi kadang ada momen tiran
[Bae Seongjae] come out?
[Bae Seongjae] yang keluar?
[Bae Seongjae] When do they come out?
[Bae Seongjae] Kapan itu keluarnya?
[Stella] Like someone just naturally in situations
[Stella] Gimana ya, seseorang itu secara natural agak
[Stella] you'd never imagine, she just says things in this fun way
[Stella] di situasi yang nggak terduga dengan seru gini
[Stella] I think there's something about how she talks. [Bae Seongjae] Suddenly makes shocking statements or something
[Stella] ngomong sesuatu kayak gini. [Bae Seongjae] Tiba-tiba agak pernyataan yang mengejutkan atau
[Bae Seongjae] Uh
[Bae Seongjae] eh
[Bae Seongjae] Like when asked 'if the members turned into stones'
[Bae Seongjae] kalau member berubah jadi batu
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha would say
[Bae Seongjae] kalau ditanya begitu, Yuha
[Bae Seongjae] she'd skip stones
[Bae Seongjae] bilang mau main lempar batu ke air
[Bae Seongjae] 'Go Stella!'
[Bae Seongjae] Ayo Stella pergi!
[Bae Seongjae] 'Here we go!' like that lol
[Bae Seongjae] Hup! sambil wkwkwk
[Bae Seongjae] This is logical in a way too, right? If they're stones, there's no other option.
[Bae Seongjae] Ini kalau dipikir-pikir juga logis sih kan? Kalau udah jadi batu ya nggak ada cara lain.
[Bae Seongjae] You have to give them the most beautiful ending.
[Bae Seongjae] Harus kasih akhir yang paling indah.
[Bae Seongjae] So when asked 'if the members became gum,' she said she'd chew them up.
[Bae Seongjae] Terus kalau ditanya member jadi permen karet gimana, bilang mau dikunyah aja.
[Stella] Thank you, Yuha.
[Stella] Terima kasih, Yuha.
[Bae Seongjae] In a way, she'd do what best serves their original purpose.
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau dipikir-pikir dia mau lakuin hal yang paling sesuai dengan tujuan aslinya.
[Bae Seongjae] Logical. Hmm.
[Bae Seongjae] Logis juga. Hmm.
[Bae Seongjae] Let me try one more. So the members turned into wheels.
[Bae Seongjae] Coba lagi deh. Kalau member berubah jadi roda.
[Yuha] Hmm.
[Yuha] Hmm.
[Bae Seongjae] They turned into wheels.
[Bae Seongjae] Berubah jadi roda.
[Bae Seongjae] What would you do?
[Bae Seongjae] Gimana dong?
[Yuha] But then there's no chance they'd turn back into people, right?
[Yuha] Tapi berarti nggak ada kemungkinan berubah jadi manusia lagi kan?
[Bae Seongjae] None. Oh, scary. The look in your eyes while asking is already scary
[Bae Seongjae] Nggak ada. Eh, serem. Udah dari tatapan nanyanya aja udah serem
[Bae Seongjae] No chance, and they can't talk either.
[Bae Seongjae] nggak ada kemungkinan, dan nggak bisa ngomong juga.
[Bae Seongjae] They're just cockroaches, but I can know who this cockroach is. But they don't know.
[Bae Seongjae] Cuma kecoa biasa tapi aku bisa tau kalau kecoa ini siapa. Tapi dia gak tau.
[Bae Seongjae] They don't know me either.
[Bae Seongjae] Dia juga gak kenal aku.
[Yuha] Then I'd call Cesco.
[Yuha] Kalau gitu panggil Rentokil.
[Bae Seongjae] Without getting my hands dirty
[Bae Seongjae] Tanpa lewat tangan aku
[Yuha] I don't think I could do it.
[Yuha] Aku kayaknya gak sanggup deh.
[Bae Seongjae] Without getting blood on my hands. But the members have schedules.
[Bae Seongjae] Gak mau kotor tangan aku. Tapi member-member kan ada jadwal.
[Bae Seongjae] So I'd call a professional company to exterminate them all.
[Bae Seongjae] Jadi panggil jasa profesional buat basmi semua.
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Makasih.
[Bae Seongjae] What if the members turned out to be aliens?
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau ternyata member-member itu alien.
[Yuha] I'd report them to NASA.
[Yuha] Lapor ke NASA.
[Bae Seongjae] Kind of outsourcing style. Right? Outsourcing. Yes. NASA, there are aliens
[Bae Seongjae] Agak kayak gaya outsourcing ya. Kan? Outsourcing. Ya. NASA, di sini ada alien
[Bae Seongjae] here. NASA would take them and experiment on them and stuff
[Bae Seongjae] Ada alien. NASA bakal bawa pergi buat eksperimen dan sebagainya
[Stella] Is that okay? [Yuha] Oh, but aliens are kind of rare
[Stella] Gak apa-apa? [Yuha] Ah, tapi alien kan langka
[Yuha] So they could help the world
[Yuha] Kan bisa membantu dunia
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, aliens are good at, uh, persuading and if we research them properly, they might
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, alien kan pintar, eh, pandai membujuk dan kalau diteliti bisa jadi membantu bumi
[Bae Seongjae] help Earth, so it's right for those brilliant people to handle it. Are you sulking?
[Bae Seongjae] Mungkin ada hal yang membantu, jadi memang orang-orang ahli yang harus menangani. Lagi ngambek?
[Stella] No.
[Stella] Enggak.
[Bae Seongjae] Stella seems to be sulking.
[Bae Seongjae] Stella kayaknya lagi ngambek deh.
[Stella] I'm not.
[Stella] Enggak kok.
[Bae Seongjae] What if the members suddenly disappeared one day?
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau suatu hari member-member tiba-tiba menghilang.
[Stella] What should I do?
[Stella] Gimana dong?
[Bae Seongjae] They disappeared. They disappeared.
[Bae Seongjae] Menghilang. Menghilang.
[Yuha] But this is just reporting them missing to the police
[Yuha] Tapi ini mah tinggal lapor polisi orang hilang
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, I don't think I can do this anymore. Last one then
[Bae Seongjae] Ah kayaknya gak bisa lanjut lagi deh. Terakhir kalau begitu
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, let me ask Stella this one. The members shrunk to the size of ants.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah ini kalau begitu aku tanya ke Stella. Member-member jadi kecil kayak semut.
[Stella] They're still people but now ant-sized
[Stella] Orangnya tapi sekarang sekecil semut
[Bae Seongjae] Right. They shrunk to ant size
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Jadi kecil kayak semut
[Stella] That sounds so fun.
[Stella] Kayaknya bakal seru banget deh.
[Stella] I'd put them in my pocket and we'd go everywhere together.
[Stella] Taruh di saku terus pergi bareng-bareng.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, take them around with you?
[Bae Seongjae] Ah dibawa-bawa gitu?
[Stella] Oh, that would be so so good. I think so, right?
[Stella] Ah pasti seru banget deh. Aku sih gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Put them on a bicycle
[Bae Seongjae] Naik sepeda
[Stella] Put them on a bicycle and sing together
[Stella] Naik sepeda terus nyanyi bareng
[Bae Seongjae] Should we try riding an 8-person bicycle then?
[Bae Seongjae] Kita naik sepeda untuk 8 orang yuk?
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha, if the members shrunk to ant size
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha, kalau member-member jadi sekecil semut
[Yuha] I'd call Cesco
[Yuha] Panggil Rentokil
[Stella] They're people though
[Stella] Itu kan manusia
[Bae Seongjae] They're people. Just shrunk to ant size. Oh, if they're small you'd just exterminate them all with Cesco?
[Bae Seongjae] Manusia. Cuma jadi kecil kayak semut. Ah, kalau kecil langsung basmi semua pakai Rentokil
[Bae Seongjae] You'd get rid of them.
[Bae Seongjae] Dibuang gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Wow.
[Bae Seongjae] Wah.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, I see. Yes. Stella would
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, gitu ya. Ya. Stella tuh
[Bae Seongjae] Right. Oh, carry them around like keychains. Oh, she would.
[Bae Seongjae] Gitu kan. Eh, kayak gantungan kunci dibawa ke mana-mana. Eh, gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Cesco - totally different outsourcing, Yuha. Mm.
[Bae Seongjae] Rentokil, outsourcing yang beda banget ya Yuha. Hmm.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, there's someone called Prince Suyang Yuha
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, ada yang bilang Yuha itu Pangeran Suyang
[Bae Seongjae] What if the members, then Stella,
[Bae Seongjae] Dan Stella
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] The members have become Tteok-kkochi addicts
[Bae Seongjae] Member-membernya udah jadi Dubai Chewy Cookie
[Stella] Uh, then eat it. You have to eat it. This can't be helped.
[Stella] Eh, ya udah makan. Harus makan. Ini gak bisa ditahan.
[Stella] You have to eat that.
[Stella] Yang begitu harus dimakan.
[Stella] Then you have to eat it.
[Stella] Ya udah harus makan.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, since you wait in line to eat it.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, soalnya ngantri buat makannya.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, how about you Yuha? [Yuha] Tteok-kkochi varies a lot
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, Yuha gimana? [Yuha] Dubai Chewy Cookie itu tiap toko
[Yuha] in taste by store. So comparing the eight different flavors
[Yuha] rasanya beda banget soalnya. Jadi seru banget bisa bandingin delapan rasa
[Yuha] That kind of fun
[Yuha] gitu
[Bae Seongjae] There's someone saying it's amazing this team stays together.
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang aneh tim ini masih bisa bertahan.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, tteok-kkochi is hard to resist. But these days, right? Yes. I'll eat it and remember.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, Dubai Chewy Cookie emang susah ditahan. Tapi zaman sekarang kan begitu? Ya. Makan biar bisa diingat.
[Bae Seongjae] This feeling. Now, this much makes me understand why she's called
[Bae Seongjae] Kayak gitu. Nah, segini udah keliatan kenapa disebut tiran
[Bae Seongjae] a tyrant. I get it perfectly now.
[Bae Seongjae] ya. Udah paham banget sekarang.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, then the next keyword is shower, which is Stella's
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, keyword selanjutnya adalah shower. Ini keyword-nya Stella
[Bae Seongjae] keyword. I heard you shower for a really long time. About how
[Bae Seongjae] nih. Katanya mandi lama banget. Kira-kira
[Bae Seongjae] much time do you spend?
[Bae Seongjae] berapa lama mandinya?
[Stella] Yes, the longest was about 1 hour and 40 minutes I think.
[Stella] Ya, paling lama itu 1 jam 40 menit lebih sedikit kayaknya.
[Bae Seongjae] 1 hour 40 minutes, that's like watching a movie. Did you watch a movie?
[Bae Seongjae] 1 jam 40 menit itu bisa nonton film satu. Nonton film ya?
[Stella] Uh I just put on music from my playlist
[Stella] Eh gak, cuma putar musik aja di playlist
[Stella] Sometimes I zone out, sometimes I sing and dance, sometimes I practice
[Stella] kadang bengong, kadang nyanyi sambil nari, kadang latihan ekspresi
[Stella] facial expressions [Bae Seongjae] So you dance in the shower, in the bathroom
[Stella] juga [Bae Seongjae] Di kamar mandi nari
[Bae Seongjae] and put on performances before coming out. You don't have an indoor bike in there, do you?
[Bae Seongjae] terus konser, keluar deh. Gak ada sepeda statis di dalam kan?
[Stella] That would be nice.
[Stella] Boleh juga tuh.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh
[Bae Seongjae] Eh
[Stella] Yes
[Stella] Ya
[Bae Seongjae] How long does it take for you Yuha? [Yuha] Me, about 20, 30 minutes.
[Bae Seongjae] Yuha berapa lama? [Yuha] Aku sekitar 20, 30 menit.
[Bae Seongjae] 20, 30 minutes. Uh, that's just right in a way. Then have the members waiting behind ever complained?
[Bae Seongjae] 20, 30 menit. Eh, pas banget. Terus member yang nunggu di belakang gak pernah komplain?
[Stella] I always, ah, it's better now but in the past I would tell everyone to shower
[Stella] Aku sih selalu, ah sekarang udah mendingan sih, dulu tuh suruh yang lain
[Stella] first, so they'd shower first and I'd shower last.
[Stella] mandi duluan, jadi aku yang paling terakhir.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, but is there a Canadian culture of long showers? I don't really know about that
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, di Kanada budayanya mandi lama gak sih? Gak tau soalnya
[Stella] I don't think so. [Bae Seongjae] It's just your preference.
[Stella] Kayaknya gak deh. [Bae Seongjae] Ini selera sendiri ya.
[Bae Seongjae] What's so good about it? Like this
[Bae Seongjae] Apanya yang enak sih?
[Stella] Just, you know, like this
[Stella] Ya gitu aja
[Stella] Mm. There's music and I like just staying still like this
[Stella] Hmm. Ada musiknya terus enak aja diem gitu
[Bae Seongjae] In the bathtub like this, just that
[Bae Seongjae] Di bathtub gitu
[Bae Seongjae] Healing?
[Bae Seongjae] healing?
[Stella] Healing time, and then singing
[Stella] Healing time, terus nyanyi juga
[Bae Seongjae] Singing and dancing too
[Bae Seongjae] Nyanyi terus nari juga
[Bae Seongjae] Looking in the mirror
[Bae Seongjae] sambil liat cermin
[Stella] Uh mirror, just looking at the wall
[Stella] Eh cermin, ya liat tembok aja
[Bae Seongjae] Uh looking at the wall, in a way there's that dry ice effect too
[Bae Seongjae] Eh liat tembok, kayak efek dry ice juga
[Bae Seongjae] with all the steam rising up
[Bae Seongjae] uapnya naik semua kan
[Bae Seongjae] Uh I see
[Bae Seongjae] Eh begitu ya
[Bae Seongjae] Have you ever sung I Got a Boy while showering?
[Bae Seongjae] Pernah nyanyi I Got a Boy waktu mandi?
[Stella] I have
[Stella] Pernah
[Stella] Yeah
[Stella] Iya
[Bae Seongjae] Right. Dorm shower
[Bae Seongjae] Gitu ya. Mandi di asrama
[Bae Seongjae] Are there any set rules? At the dorm?
[Bae Seongjae] Ada aturan khusus gak? Di asrama?
[Stella] Uh, I don't think so [Yuha] Clean up after yourself and stuff
[Stella] Eh, kayaknya gak ada [Yuha] Beres-beres aja yang penting
[Bae Seongjae] That's about it. Uh,
[Bae Seongjae] Segitu aja. Oh,
[Bae Seongjae] So are there any established dorm life rules for Hearts2Hearts members?
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau gitu ada aturan hidup di asrama yang udah ditetapkan buat member Hearts2Hearts?
[Stella] We have different dorms so I don't know about here, but at our dorm
[Stella] Kita asramanya beda sih, jadi yang sini gak tau, tapi asrama kita
[Stella] Just clean up after eating and keep your own stuff organized.
[Stella] Cuma bersihin makanan dengan baik, terus rapiin barang sendiri aja
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, keep it clean.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, pake yang bersih
[Stella] Just keep it clean.
[Stella] Pake yang bersih aja
[Bae Seongjae] Common areas. [Yuha] We also just keep it clean.
[Bae Seongjae] Ruang bersama [Yuha] Kita juga pake yang bersih
[Bae Seongjae] Keep it clean. Have there been any problems so far?
[Bae Seongjae] Yang bersih. Selama ini pernah ada masalah gak?
[Stella] No.
[Stella] Gak
[Bae Seongjae] Haven't gotten upset about anything?
[Bae Seongjae] Pernah ngambek gak?
[Stella] No. None.
[Stella] Gak. Gak pernah
[Bae Seongjae] Seems like this question is making you upset
[Bae Seongjae] Kayaknya ngambek sama pertanyaan ini
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. So, H2H's bathroom is Stella's
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Nah, kamar mandi H2H jadi ruang karaoke sendiri Stella
[Bae Seongjae] solo karaoke room. So is there anything missing at the dorm? Borrowing this opportunity to ask the CEO, we won nine rookie awards, so every time we win an award
[Bae Seongjae] Kalau gitu ada yang kurang di asrama gak? Kita pinjam kesempatan ini sama CEO
[Bae Seongjae] we won nine rookie awards, so every time we win an award
[Bae Seongjae] Kita udah dapet sembilan penghargaan rookie, setiap dapet penghargaan gini
[Bae Seongjae] shouldn't we get some new appliances added? Wouldn't that be nice?
[Bae Seongjae] Bagus juga kan kalau elektronik rumah tangga nambah satu-satu gitu?
[Stella] Mm.
[Stella] Hmm
[Stella] I do wish for separate rooms
[Stella] Aku sih pengennya kamar sendiri
[Bae Seongjae] Separate rooms - who's your roommate now?
[Bae Seongjae] Kamar sendiri, sekarang roommate-nya siapa?
[Stella] Right now I'm sharing with A-NA.
[Stella] Sekarang aku sekamar sama A-NA
[Bae Seongjae] Mm. Isn't it about time you each get your own room?
[Bae Seongjae] Hmm. Kamar sendiri, udah waktunya punya kamar masing-masing kan?
[Stella] Mm. Yeah.
[Stella] Hmm. Iya
[Yuha] Separate rooms would be good.
[Yuha] Kamar sendiri bagus
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Everyone agrees on separate rooms.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Kamar sendiri setuju
[Yuha] Massage chair? [Bae Seongjae] Massage chair. Ah, just lie down like this and, just once
[Yuha] Kursi pijat? [Bae Seongjae] Kursi pijat. Ah, tiduran gini terus sekali eh, sekali
[Bae Seongjae] satisfyingly uh, release all that stiffness. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Bangga gitu eh, bisa ilangin pegal-pegal. Iya
[Bae Seongjae] Good. Again Yuha has that grandma vibe
[Bae Seongjae] Bagus. Yuha emang agak berasa nenek
[Bae Seongjae] Massage chair.
[Bae Seongjae] Kursi pijat
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. How about an indoor bike?
[Bae Seongjae] Iya. Gimana sepeda statis?
[Stella] That would be so good.
[Stella] Bagus banget
[Bae Seongjae] So good?
[Bae Seongjae] Bagus banget?
[Stella] Please.
[Stella] Tolong banget
[Yuha] Or beds with electric blankets, heated mattress pads - we need stuff like that.
[Yuha] Atau kasur itu selimut listrik matras pemanas gitu perlu banget
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, you should have those right away. Right? Good. Yes. Is the TV size okay?
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, yang begituan sih harus ada langsung kan. Kan? Bagus. Iya. TV ukurannya gimana?
[Stella] Really really really big
[Stella] Besar banget yang gede banget
[Bae Seongjae] Oh it's big. Uh, good. Yes
[Bae Seongjae] Oh gede ya. Oh bagus. Iya
[Bae Seongjae] I think these things will happen right away.
[Bae Seongjae] Kayaknya langsung bisa nih
[Bae Seongjae] Now, next keyword - rockstar.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah keyword selanjutnya rockstar
[Stella] Mm
[Stella] Hmm
[Bae Seongjae] They call Stella a rock star.
[Bae Seongjae] Stella disebut sebagai rockstar.
[Bae Seongjae] Are you a rock star in the bathroom too?
[Bae Seongjae] Di kamar mandi juga rockstar?
[Stella] Yeah, I think so.
[Stella] Ya, kayaknya gitu.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, Soda Bottle Baby says Stella's good at singing songs in rock versions.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, Soda Bottle Baby bilang Stella jago nyanyi lagu versi rock.
[Bae Seongjae] Can any song become a rock version? [Stella] Yes, doesn't matter.
[Bae Seongjae] Lagu apa aja bisa jadi versi rock? [Stella] Ya, nggak masalah.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, then Girls' Generation sunbaenims
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, kalau gitu Girls' Generation sunbae-nim
[Stella] I Got a Boy? [Bae Seongjae] Yes, try it in rock style.
[Stella] I Got a Boy? [Bae Seongjae] Ya, coba versi rock.
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone says it sounds like a rich family's doorbell.
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang kayak nada dering rumah orang kaya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Someone asked to do it again, and someone said it's like Doraemon.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Ada juga yang bilang minta lagi, ada yang bilang kayak Doraemon.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone just asked if that was Pengsoo.
[Bae Seongjae] Barusan ada yang nanya itu Pengsoo ya?
[Bae Seongjae] And can you also play guitar by any chance? If you're a rock star.
[Bae Seongjae] Terus bisa main gitar juga nggak? Kalau rockstar.
[Stella] Uh, of course.
[Stella] Eh, tentu saja.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh.
[Stella] Ah, should I try?
[Stella] Ah, mau coba?
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Stella] Ah, give me some reaction
[Stella] Ah, kasih reaksi dong
[Stella] Ah, wait a moment.
[Stella] Ah, tunggu sebentar.
[Stella] Uh. Yeah. Uh,
[Stella] Eh. Ya. Eh,
[Bae Seongjae] Right. Someone says it's too scary. Sorry, Stella. Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Gitu. Ada yang bilang terlalu serem. Maaf ya, Stella.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, and guitar playing has been revealed, but drum playing
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, terus main gitar udah pernah dipublik tapi main drum
[Bae Seongjae] is still unrevealed, I heard. [Stella] That's right.
[Bae Seongjae] katanya masih belum dipublik ya? [Stella] Betul.
[Bae Seongjae] Could you possibly show us a bit of drum practice
[Bae Seongjae] Mungkin di sini bisa tunjukin sedikit latihan drum
[Bae Seongjae] air drums here?
[Bae Seongjae] air drum?
[Stella] Air drums, got it. Uh,
[Stella] Air drum, oke. Eh,
[Stella] Pungchi
[Stella] Pungchi
[Stella] Pungdu-pung
[Stella] Pungdupung
[Stella] I'll stop here. Yeah. Wow
[Stella] Sampai sini aja ya. Ya. Wa
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] The chat says 'Why does that kid do everything?' 'Why does she do everything?' 'Don't overdo it.'
[Bae Seongjae] Di chatting ada yang bilang kenapa anak itu bisa semua? Kenapa bisa semua? Jangan dipaksa.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone calling her Dahyeon-ah
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang Dahyun-ah
[Bae Seongjae] First of all, when starting, this is prettier.
[Bae Seongjae] Awalnya ini yang ini lebih cantik.
[Stella] Yeah.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Someone says to put Dahyeon to sleep now
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang Dahyun udah tidur aja
[Bae Seongjae] Someone says 'Dahyeon-ah, learn to say no sometimes.'
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang Dahyun-ah, kadang nolak juga dong.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, Park Seonghyeon says Stella can play guitar, drums, and bass
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, Park Sunghyun bilang Stella bisa gitar, drum, bass juga
[Bae Seongjae] and Yuha plays piano well. If all eight Hearts2Hearts members formed a band,
[Bae Seongjae] dan Yuha jago main piano kan. Kalau Hearts2Hearts delapan orang semua bikin band
[Bae Seongjae] what instrument would you assign to each?
[Bae Seongjae] masing-masing bakal dikasih alat musik apa?
[Stella] Uh, I'll start with Carmen unnie.
[Stella] Eh, mulai dari Carmen unnie dulu ya.
[Stella] Carmen unnie is
[Stella] Carmen unnie
[Stella] kind of percussion
[Stella] kayak perkusi
[Bae Seongjae] Percussion
[Bae Seongjae] Perkusi
[Stella] Yeah. Kind of
[Stella] Ya. Kayak
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, this pronunciation of 'percussion'
[Bae Seongjae] Oh perkusi, pelafalannya
[Stella] Kinda, you know?
[Stella] Kayak tau kan?
[Yuha] What's that?
[Yuha] Apaan sih itu?
[Stella] That kinda
[Stella] Itu kayak
[Bae Seongjae] Drums?
[Bae Seongjae] Drum?
[Stella] Like triangles and stuff like that, various instruments [Yuha] Percussion instruments
[Stella] Ada triangle juga ada yang ini juga kayak berbagai alat musik [Yuha] Alat musik perkusi
[Stella] Oh yes
[Stella] Oh yes
[Yuha] Jiwoo unnie always says she wants to play electric guitar.
[Yuha] Jiwoo unnie itu kayak selalu bilang mau main gitar listrik.
[Yuha] So electric
[Yuha] Jadi elektrik
[Yuha] And you're piano
[Yuha] Terus kamu piano
[Bae Seongjae] Piano's the winner [Yuha] guitar
[Bae Seongjae] Piano yang menang [Yuha] Ada gitar
[Stella] JUUN is
[Stella] JUUN itu
[Yuha] JUUN should do something cool
[Yuha] JUUN kayaknya harus yang keren deh
[Stella] Drums and A-NA is
[Stella] Drum sama A-NA
[Yuha] What's this? Castanets
[Yuha] Ini apaan? Kastanyet
[Stella] Castanets
[Stella] Kastanyet
[Bae Seongjae] It's surprisingly hard. You gotta keep the beat. Yeah. What about Ian?
[Bae Seongjae] Lumayan susah loh. Harus sesuai irama soalnya. Ya. Ian gimana?
[Stella] Ian is sogo
[Stella] Ian itu sogo
[Bae Seongjae] Sogo?
[Bae Seongjae] Sogo?
[Stella] Sogo
[Stella] Sogo
[Bae Seongjae] The genre's getting really broad.
[Bae Seongjae] Genre-nya jadi makin luas nih.
[Stella] Yeah. YE-ON is
[Stella] Ya. YE-ON itu
[Stella] Vocals?
[Stella] Vokal?
[Bae Seongjae] Vocals, oh like that, yeah
[Bae Seongjae] Vokal oh gitu ya
[Bae Seongjae] Suddenly sogo? Why does Yuha's taste suddenly
[Bae Seongjae] Kok tiba-tiba sogo? Kenapa Yuha selera musiknya tiba-tiba jadi kayak gini
[Bae Seongjae] jump around sometimes. Like her food preferences too. Oh, fusion-style
[Bae Seongjae] Ada kalanya loncat-loncat gitu. Selera makanan juga gitu. Oh jadi fusion
[Bae Seongjae] There's no bass. Bass
[Bae Seongjae] Gak ada bass nih. Bass
[Stella] Ah
[Stella] Ah
[Stella] Bass, I'll do the bass.
[Stella] Bass bass aku yang main deh.
[Bae Seongjae] Both?
[Bae Seongjae] Dua-duanya?
[Stella] Both at the same time [Bae Seongjae] Oh, we might see a crossover group later.
[Stella] Dua sekaligus [Bae Seongjae] Oh, grup crossover bisa kita lihat nanti.
[Bae Seongjae] Alright. Got it. Let's do K-pop
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, begitu. Oke. Mari buat K-Pop
[Bae Seongjae] someone said. Yeah. So like this
[Bae Seongjae] Ada yang bilang begitu. Ya. Nah, begini
[Bae Seongjae] uh, we had keyword talk time with everyone.
[Bae Seongjae] Kita sudah ngobrol keyword talk time bareng kalian semua.
[Bae Seongjae] This time we have that balance game, ah
[Bae Seongjae] Kali ini balance game ah,
[Bae Seongjae] time's already up.
[Bae Seongjae] Waktu sudah habis nih.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah. We sadly have another segment prepared but
[Bae Seongjae] Ah. Sayang ada korner lain yang udah disiapkan
[Bae Seongjae] let's listen to ads and say goodbye to you two.
[Bae Seongjae] Dengerin iklan dulu terus pamitan sama kalian berdua ya.
[Stella] It went by so fast.
[Stella] Cepet banget berlalunya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh really? [Stella] It was fun.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh gitu ya? [Stella] Seru sih.
[Bae Seongjae] Aw thank you. This is always a comfortable
[Bae Seongjae] Ah makasih. Kapan aja dateng main ke
[Bae Seongjae] place so come visit anytime.
[Bae Seongjae] tempat yang nyaman ini.
[Staff] Did the explanation go
[Staff] Penjelasannya terus
[Staff] all the way through?
[Staff] jadi?
[Staff] Ah
[Staff] Ah
[Staff] Should we just skip it?
[Staff] eh ngga usah aja gimana?
[Staff] Yeah. The time is
[Staff] Ya. Waktunya
[Staff] Oh, you're not doing it at all? [Staff] Uh no, the time has gone over 40 minutes
[Staff] Ah jadi beneran ngga usah? [Staff] Eh ngga, waktunya udah lebih dari 40 menit
[Staff] Oh I see, then
[Staff] Ah gitu ya, jadi kalau begitu
[Staff] Uh
[Staff] eh
[Staff] We should do closing remarks
[Staff] salam penutup harus
[Bae Seongjae] Let's just do closing remarks and skip the ASMR
[Bae Seongjae] Cuma salam penutup aja, ASMR-nya dilewat
[Staff] When I was explaining earlier, I covered everything else but didn't explain the ASMR part
[Staff] Tadi waktu saya jelasin yang lain udah dijelasin semua tapi ini belum ASMR
[Staff] Then
[Staff] Kalau gitu
[Staff] Uh so if you want to do it, at the very end
[Staff] eh jadi kalau mau lakuin, paling akhir
[Staff] If I ask you to do it at the very end, I don't think we can do that part, so just this would be fine.
[Staff] paling akhir aja tolong, soalnya bagian ini kayaknya ngga bisa dilakuin, jadi cuma ini aja.
[Stella] Okay. Yeah. With ASMR
[Stella] Ya. Ya. Dengan ASMR
[Bae Seongjae] Skip the ASMR, just regular
[Bae Seongjae] ASMR dilewat aja, biasa aja
[Staff] Just make the sound please.
[Staff] Bikin suara aja.
[Stella] Okay.
[Stella] Oke.
[Stella] What are you doing after this?
[Stella] Habis ini ngapain?
[Bae Seongjae] Huh?
[Bae Seongjae] Hah?
[Bae Seongjae] Why are you following me after this?
[Bae Seongjae] Habis ini kenapa ikut-ikut?
[Bae Seongjae] Junior, to the rooftop
[Bae Seongjae] Hoobae ke atap
[Bae Seongjae] It feels like you're telling me to follow you
[Bae Seongjae] berasa disuruh ikut
[Stella] Well, yeah
[Stella] Ya apa
[Bae Seongjae] Why?
[Bae Seongjae] Kenapa?
[Stella] No.
[Stella] Bukan.
[Bae Seongjae] I have a live broadcast.
[Bae Seongjae] Ada siaran langsung soalnya.
[Stella] Ah
[Stella] Ah
[Yuha] Another radio live broadcast?
[Yuha] Radio siaran langsung lagi?
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. This is a recording right now. Yes. Live broadcast.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Sekarang rekaman. Ya. Siaran langsung.
[Bae Seongjae] Yeah. Why, did I do something wrong
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Kenapa saya ada yang salah salah
[Stella] No, no.
[Stella] Bukan. Bukan.
[Bae Seongjae] Uh, do I need to get scolded?
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, harus dimarahin ya?
[Staff] Alright, let's go.
[Staff] Oke, mulai.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Now, Sunday March 1st, Bae Seongjae's TEN today
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Oke, 1 Maret hari Minggu Bae Seongjae's TEN hari ini
[Bae Seongjae] we were with Hearts2Hearts' Yuha and Stella. Ah, time went by
[Bae Seongjae] bareng Hearts2Hearts Yuha Stella berdua. Ah, waktu cepet banget
[Bae Seongjae] so fast, it's such a shame.
[Bae Seongjae] berlalu jadi sayang banget.
[Bae Seongjae] Just when things were getting fun, like we were about to have some real laughs
[Bae Seongjae] Sekarang baru mulai seru gitu loh, kayaknya bakal rame banget
[Bae Seongjae] It's disappointing. We should've had a two-hour broadcast
[Bae Seongjae] sayang. Harusnya siaran dua jam
[Bae Seongjae] Today was so fun for us, I don't know how it was for you two.
[Bae Seongjae] hari ini seru banget tapi ngga tau gimana perasaan kalian berdua.
[Stella] I had so much fun.
[Stella] Aku seru banget.
[Stella] It was so fun. Yeah. Thank you for making us feel comfortable.
[Stella] Seru banget. Ya. Terima kasih udah bikin nyaman. Ini
[Bae Seongjae] You must be tired but you came to B-TEN, we're so grateful. Really, to our
[Bae Seongjae] Capek tapi dateng lagi ke Bae-TEN, seneng banget. Beneran
[Bae Seongjae] listeners, could you please say goodbye one by one.
[Bae Seongjae] tolong sapa pendengar sekali-kali.
[Yuha] Today was so much fun. Next time when we make a comeback, please invite us
[Yuha] Hari ini seru banget, kalau next comeback tolong panggil lagi
[Yuha] I'll come anytime. Please listen to RUDE a lot. Thank you.
[Yuha] kapan aja bakal dateng. RUDE banyak-banyak didengerin ya. Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes. Thank you. Yeah.
[Bae Seongjae] Ya. Terima kasih. Ya.
[Stella] Yeah. Yeah. I also had so so much fun today and Bae Seongjae was so so good to us
[Stella] Ya. Ya. Aku juga hari ini seru banget dan Bae Seongjae juga baik banget
[Stella] so thank you so much. You're the best.
[Stella] terima kasih banget. Keren banget.
[Stella] Please invite us again.
[Stella] Undang lagi ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, this is good.
[Bae Seongjae] Eh, ini bagus nih.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, good. Yuha, you can't forget that name.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, bagus. Yuha, jangan lupa namanya ya.
[Yuha] Bae Seongjae.
[Yuha] Bae Seongjae.
[Bae Seongjae] Bae Seongjae. Yes. Uh, seems like you got a bit
[Bae Seongjae] Bae Seongjae. Ya. Eh, kayaknya agak
[Bae Seongjae] confused. Well, thank you for coming and next time
[Bae Seongjae] bingung tadi. Nah, terima kasih sudah datang dan
[Bae Seongjae] whenever you have time, feel free to come hang out anytime. We're always open.
[Bae Seongjae] kalau ada waktu lagi kapan aja main aja santai. Kita selalu terbuka kok.
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Now, we met the two from Hearts2Hearts on Produce 1077. I'll ask you two to do the closing remarks.
[Bae Seongjae] Nah, Produce 1077 ketemu sama Hearts2Hearts berdua. Salam penutup minta tolong sama kalian berdua ya.
[Yuha] Yes. This has been Hearts2Hearts' Yuha.
[Yuha] Ya. Sampai di sini Hearts2Hearts Yuha.
[Stella] I was Stella. Then we'll turn off the lights.
[Stella] Aku Stella. Sekarang mau matiin lampunya.
[Stella] Dream of Hearts2Hearts. [Yuha] Dream of Hearts2Hearts.
[Stella] Mimpi Hearts2Hearts ya. [Yuha] Mimpi Hearts2Hearts ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah terima kasih.
[Staff] The product introduction
[Staff] Intro produk
[Staff] We decided to take turns with Gilly's
[Staff] sama Gilly bergantian
[Bae Seongjae] Yes?
[Bae Seongjae] Ya?
[Staff] In March
[Staff] bulan Maret
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Terima kasih.
[Staff] Just one favor please.
[Staff] Satu aja tolong.
[Stella] Yes. Yes.
[Stella] Ya. Ya.
[Stella] That game
[Stella] Game itu
[Staff] We decided to get two. Now, can we go straight to this?
[Staff] Dua ini udah siap. Nah, ini langsung boleh gak?
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Ya.
[Staff] Just read it once.
[Staff] Sekali baca aja dulu.
[Staff] Ah, wait. When this red thing comes on.
[Staff] Ah, sebentar. Kalau yang merah ini masuk ya.
[Stella] Ah, yes.
[Stella] Ah, ya.
[Yuha] Hello. We're Hearts2Hearts' Yuha and Stella, currently promoting with our new song RUDE.
[Yuha] Halo. Hearts2Hearts Yuha Stella yang lagi aktif dengan lagu baru RUDE.
[유한] We'll introduce the gifts from Bae Seongjae's TEN. The Han Muncheol dashcam that catches sudden acceleration evidence.
[Yuha] Bakal kasih tahu hadiah dari BeTen. Blackbox Han Muncheol yang nangkep bukti akselerasi mendadak.
[Stella] Beat the Day 100 Times is giving away a game-type weight management device, so participate and take the gift
[Stella] Dari Haru Reul Iginun 100beon ada alat pengatur berat badan tipe game, jadi ikutan dan ambil hadiahnya
[Stella] Sorry.
[Stella] Maaf.
[Bae Seongjae] Take it if you want it. Don't if you don't.
[Bae Seongjae] Mau ambil ya ambil. Gak mau ya gak usah.
[Stella] Yes. Do I need to do it again? Uh
[Stella] Ya. Harus ulang lagi gak? Eh
[Staff] From 'Beat the Day'
[Staff] Dari Haru reul iginun
[Stella] Beat the Day, Beat the Day 100 Times is giving away a game-type weight
[Stella] Haru reul Haru reul iginun 100beon ada alat pengatur berat
[Stella] management device, so participate and take the gift.
[Stella] badan tipe game, jadi ikutan dan ambil hadiahnya ya.
[Yuha] Please also love Hearts2Hearts' song RUDE a lot.
[Yuha] Lagu RUDE Hearts2Hearts juga banyak-banyak disayang ya.
[Bae Seongjae] Thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] Terima kasih.
[Staff] Thank you.
[Staff] Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Take it or don't, whatever you want.
[Bae Seongjae] Mau ambil atau gak terserah.
[Bae Seongjae] Thank you. You should be resting but you came here again, so thank you so much
[Bae Seongjae] Terima kasih. Aduh harusnya istirahat eh malah datang lagi jadi
[Bae Seongjae] fun. [Yuha] Bye.
[Bae Seongjae] menyenangkan. [Yuha] Dah.
[Stella] Bye.
[Stella] Dah.
[Bae Seongjae] Come closer for a greeting. Oh, we need to take a photo first. Hey, photo first.
[Bae Seongjae] Ayo salam dulu dari dekat. Ah, foto dulu. Eh, foto dulu ya.
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Iya.
[Staff] We'll go out this way.
[Staff] Kita foto kayak gini nih.
[Staff] Act like proper juniors, like proper juniors when taking the photo.
[Staff] Agak kayak junior gitu, kayak junior.
[Writer] Could you two come forward a bit please
[Writer] Kalian berdua maju sedikit ke depan
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Iya.
[Stella] This is our RUDE pose, like this.
[Stella] Ini pose RUDE kami kayak gini.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, okay. Okay.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, oke. Oke.
[Stella] Yes.
[Stella] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Like this.
[Bae Seongjae] Kayak gini.
[Bae Seongjae] Yes.
[Bae Seongjae] Iya.
[Bae Seongjae] Is it okay if I turn like this? [Stella] Right hand up
[Bae Seongjae] Putar kayak gini nggak apa-apa? [Stella] Tangan kanan ke atas
[Stella] covering the face.
[Stella] Tutupi wajah.
[Writer] Hold on.
[Writer] Sebentar ya.
[Writer] One, two, three.
[Writer] Satu, dua, tiga.
[Writer] One, two, three. Thank you.
[Writer] Satu, dua, tiga. Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah, thank you.
[Bae Seongjae] Ah terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Oh, the song is so good. [Writer] Please take one selfie
[Bae Seongjae] Aduh lagunya bagus banget. [Writer] Selca sekali aja
[Stella] Yes. Thank you.
[Stella] Iya. Terima kasih.
[Bae Seongjae] Come close for a greeting once
[Bae Seongjae] Salam sekali dari dekat
[Stella] Thank you. It was so fun.
[Stella] Terima kasih. Seru banget.
[Stella] Bye
[Stella] Dah
[Yuha] RUDE
[Yuha] RUDE
[Stella] Please give us lots of love
[Stella] Banyak perhatian ya
[Stella] Bye [Bae Seongjae] I learned it. RUDE
[Stella] Dah [Bae Seongjae] Udah belajar. RUDE
[Stella] Thank you.
[Stella] Terima kasih.